英文字幕Subtitles by explosiveskull
-= www.OpenSubtitles.org =-
好吧 各位 我們最後再來一次
All right, let's do this one last time.
我叫彼得 帕克
My name is Peter Parker.
我被一隻受過輻射的蜘蛛咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
在過去的10年裏
And for 10 years...
我是這世上
I've been the one
唯一的
and only
蜘蛛俠
Spider-Man.
剩下的你們都知道了
I'm pretty sure you know the rest.
能力越大 責任就越大
With great power comes great responsibility.
拯救了不少人  墜入過愛河  拯救過城市
I saved a bunch of people, fell in love, saved the city.
又一次的拯救城市
And then I saved the city again.
一次又一次
And again and again
的拯救城市
and again.
我做到了
And I did, uh...
而且做的很好
I did this.
♪ Get on up Get yourself together ♪
♪ Drive that funky soul ♪
我們不需要光談論這個
We don't really talk about this.
看我還出過漫畫 還有同款麥片食物
Look, I'm a comic book. I'm a cereal.
和聖誕專輯
Did a Christmas album.
是一首很棒的主題歌
I have an excellent theme song.
♪ Spider-man Spider-man ♪
還有不怎麼樣的冰激凌
And a so-so popsicle.
我的意思是 看上去很糟糕
I mean, I've looked worse.
經歷過這些事後
But after everything...
我仍然喜歡做蜘蛛俠
I still love being Spider-Man.
我是說誰不喜歡呢
I mean, who wouldn't?
不管被打敗多少次
So no matter how many hits I take...
我最終總是會爬起來的
...I always find a way to come back.
因為能平衡這個城市的
Because the only thing standing between this city and oblivion
只有我
is me.
因為蜘蛛俠只有唯一的一個
There's only one Spider-Man.
而且你現在就在看著他
And you're lookin' at him.
哦
♪ Ooh ♪
哦 哦 哦
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
無需多說
♪ Needless to say... ♪
儘管她身上充滿了危險因素
♪ Nevertheless Callin' it quits ♪
-我要叫停了 寶貝 我已成了一具殘骸  -邁爾斯
- ♪ Now, baby, I'm a wreck ♪ - RIO: Miles!
上學時間到了
Miles, papa, time for school!
邁爾斯
Miles!
-邁爾斯 -聽到了
- Miles! - Yeah! Yeah?
去學校的行李打包好了嗎
Are you finished packing for school?
好了
Yeah.
在熨我最後一件襯衫
Just ironing my last shirt.
♪ You're a sunflower... ♪
拜託  你現在是個成年人了
Come on! You a grown man now.
-讓我們給這些老師看看  -邁爾斯
- Let's show these teachers that. - Miles!
我的筆記本電腦呢
Where's my laptop?
如果你想讓我開車送你  我們現在就得走了
If you want me to drive you, we gotta go now.
不用了爸爸 我自己走
No, Dad, I'll walk.
-讓我當一次你的私人司機吧 -不用了
- Personal chauffeur going once. - It's okay.
-邁爾斯該走了 -再等一下
- Miles! Gotta go. - In a minute!
-該走了 -再等一下
- Gotta go. - In a minute!
媽媽 我要走了
Mom, I gotta go.
再等一下啊
In a minute.
我們週五見
See you Friday.
看 誰回來了 最近怎樣 老兄
Look who's back. Yo, what's going on, bro?
嘿  我只是路過 你還好嗎
Hey, I'm just walking by. How you doin'?
邁爾斯  你昨晚感覺到了地震
Yo, Miles! You feel that earthquake last night?
你在說什麼 我昨晚睡得像個嬰兒似的
What you talkin' about? I slept like a baby last night.
-新學校怎麼樣 -輕而易舉
- How's that new school? - So easy.
-我們想你 邁爾斯 -你想我 但我還住在這裏
- We miss you, Miles. - You miss me? I still live here!
等等 你想我
Wait, you miss me?
Contra!
不是吧
Oh, come on.
認真的嗎 爸 我走去學校就好了
Seriously, Dad. Walking would've been fine.
星期六的時候你就可以邊走
You can walk plenty on Saturday
邊把你那些隨意粘貼的貼紙拿下來了
when you peel those stickers off.
你看到我了 我不覺得那是我
You saw that? I don't know if that was me.
還有你昨天在克林頓貼的兩個
And the two from yesterday on Clinton.
好吧 是我
Yeah, those were me.
看哪裏 一家新開的咖啡店
Look at that. Another new coffee shop.
-你看到了嗎 -看到了
- You see that? - Totally. Yeah.
-那個叫什麼 -泡沫派對
- What's that one called? - Foam Party.
泡沫派對  不是吧
"Foam Party"? Come on.
每個人只穿亞麻布  你看到了嗎
And everyone is just linin' up. You see that?
我看到了
I see it.
那是咖啡店還是迪斯科舞廳
Is that a coffee shop or a disco?
爸 你真老土
Dad, you're old, man.
昨晚有許多關於
There are multiple reports
神秘地震事件的報道
of another mysterious seismic event last night.
據知情者瞭解 蜘蛛俠正在調查這件事
Sources close to Spider-Man say he's looking into the problem.
蜘蛛俠 一個帶著小面具到處
Spider-Man. I mean, this guy swings in once a day,
蕩來蕩去 我行我素的人 對吧
zip-zap-zop in his little mask and answers to no one. Right?
是的 老爸
Yeah, Dad. Yeah.
與此同時 我們這人冒著生命危險
Meanwhile, my guys are out there,
而且不用面具
- lives on the line, no masks. - Uh-huh.
-我們露出我們的臉  -開快點 我認識這些人
- We show our faces. - Speed up. I know these kids.
能力越大  責任越大
With great ability comes great accountability.
這句話可不是這麼說的
That's not even how the saying goes.
不過我確實喜歡他的麥片  我會告訴他的
I do like his cereal, though. I'll give him that.
哦 天哪 警察不是能闖紅燈嗎
Oh, my gosh. Don't cops run red lights?
是的 有些會 但你爸爸不會
Oh, yeah, some do. But not your dad.
♪ My memories keep begging ♪
♪ For someone else ♪
♪ I know this feeling, yes I know it very well ♪
為什麼我不能回布魯克林中學
Why can't I go back to Brooklyn Middle?
已經給你兩個星期的時間了
You've given it two weeks.
我們完全不用討論這些的
We're not having this conversation.
我只是覺得這所新學校是精英學校
I just think that this new school is elitist.
-精英學校 -我還是喜歡上
- "Elitist"? - And I would prefer to be
普通學校和普通人在一起
at a normal school among the people.
「普通人」這些就是普通人
"The people"? These are your people.
我之所以能在這裏是因為我撞了大運
I'm only here 'cause I won that stupid lottery.
胡說  你和其他人一樣通過了入學考試
No way. You passed the entry test just like everybody else.
明明有那麼好的機會  你要毀了它嗎
You have an opportunity here. You wanna blow that?
想像你叔叔那樣嗎
You wanna end up like your uncle?
艾倫叔叔怎麼了 他人很好
What's wrong with Uncle Aaron? He's a good guy.
每個人都有自己的選擇
We all make choices in life.
我不覺得自己有得選
It doesn't feel like I have a choice right now.
你確實沒有
You don't!
我愛你  邁爾斯
I love you, Miles.
好啦 知道了  我們週五見
Yeah, I know, Dad. See you Friday.
-你應該也對我說 我愛你 -爸爸你沒有開玩笑吧
- You gotta say "I love you" Back. - Dad, are you serious?
我要聽你說 我愛你爸爸
I wanna hear it. "I love you, Dad."
你真要我說
You wanna hear me say it?
這是學校門口
You're dropping me off at a school.
-我愛你爸爸 -看看周圍
- "I love you, Dad." - Look at this place.
爸爸我愛你
"Dad, I love you."
Dad, I love you.
收到
That's a copy.
把鞋帶繫好
Tie your shoes, please.
我愛你爸爸
"I love you, Dad."
嘿 早上好 你好啊
Hey, good morning. How you doin'?
-需要幫忙繫鞋帶嗎 -收到
- Weekend was short, huh? - "That's a copy."
天啊 真是尷尬
Oh, my gosh! This is embarrassing.
我們穿的是同一件夾克
We wore the same jacket.
嘿 你鞋帶鬆了
Hey. Your shoe's untied.
好了 我知道 這就是個性
Yeah, I'm aware. It's a choice.
♪ Theory is that All matter is composed ♪
♪ Of at least three ♪
♪ Fundamental particles ♪
誰能解決這個xy的問題
Who can solve this for XY?
這就叫做 三段論法
And that is known as a syllogism.
回去讀完《遠大前程》的兩個章節
Read two chapters of Great Expectations.
隨堂測試容積和壓力
A take-home quiz on volumetric pressure.
五頁紙的論文 結論是重點
Five-page essay with your conclusions stressed.
會有無數種可能性
...countless other possibilities.
在另一個宇宙我可能穿的是紅衣服
There could be a universe where I am wearing red.
又或者是皮褲子
Or wearing leather pants.
偷偷溜進來的莫拉萊斯先生  你又遲到了
Mr. Morales. Movin' in the dark. You're late again.
愛因斯坦說過時間是相對的  不是嗎
Einstein said time was relative, right?
或許我沒有遲到 也許只是你們早到了
Maybe I'm not late. Maybe you guys are early.
抱歉我只是覺得太安靜了
Sorry. It was just so quiet.
你是想繼續站著呢
Would you like to keep standing there,
還是坐下
or do you wanna sit down?
我們所處的宇宙  其實是多個平行宇宙中的一個
Our universe is, in fact, one of many parallel universes
這些平行宇宙是同時存在的
happening at the exact same time.
多虧了菲斯克家族科研基因會的所有人
Thanks to everyone here at the Fisk Family Foundation...
-我喜歡你的笑話 -真的嗎
- I liked your joke. - Really?
其實不好笑 所以我才會笑
I mean, it wasn't funny. That's why I laughed.
不過想法不錯  所以我喜歡
But it was smart, so I liked it.
我好像之前沒見過你
I don't think
我以前見過你
I've seen you before.
Every choice that we make
都會創造出各種可能性
would create countless other possibilities.
而這些可能性是無窮的
A what-if to infinity.
零蛋  在多拿幾個零分
A zero? A few more of those,
你應該就會把我踢出去了吧
you'd probably have to kick me outta here, huh?
或許我不適合這個學校
Maybe I'm just not right for this school.
如果一個人閉著眼睛
If a person wearing a blindfold picked the answers
在一堆判斷題裏隨便亂選
on a true-or-false quiz at random,
你猜準確率是多少
do you know what score they would get?
-百分之五十 -回答正確
- 50%? - That's right!
能正確避開所有正確答案
The only way to get all the answers wrong
那就證明你其實全都會
is to know which answers are right.
你故意想被開除
You're trying to quit.
我是不會答應的
And I'm not gonna let you.
我要罰你寫篇關於自己的文章
I'm assigning you a personal essay.
不是關於物理  而是關於你自己的
Not about physics, but about you,
你想成為 什麼樣的人
and what kind of person you want to be.
- ♪ Unh. Unh ♪ - ♪ Unh. Unh ♪
♪ Come on ♪
♪ Ha, sicker than Your average ♪
♪ Poppa twist cabbage Off instinct ♪
♪ Don't think ♪
♪ My Detroit players, timbs for My hooligans in Brooklyn ♪
♪ Dead right, if the head Right, Biggie there e'rynight ♪
♪ Never lose, never choose to Bruise crews who ♪
- ♪ Do something to us... ♪ - ♪ Come on ♪
艾倫叔叔  嘿 嚇一跳吧
Uncle Aaron! Hey! Were you scared?
想領教一下嗎
You want that?
學校怎麼樣
What's up with school?
好得不行  朋友多到樂翻天
Going great! Got tons of friends.
總不見得一無是處吧
You can't tell me it's all that bad there.
聰明的姑娘總是那麼迷人
Smart girls is where it's at.
哪裏應該有許多才是
Place must be full of 'em.
不  沒這回事  根本沒有
No, there's no one.
做我的侄子
Yo, I can't have no nephew of mine
可不能那麼沒戲
on the streets with no game.
誰說我沒戲了 有個新來的姑娘
Hey, I got game. There's a new girl.
你懂的 他還挺喜歡我的
Actually, you know, she's kinda into me.
你懂的
You know how it is.
他叫什麼
What's her name?
你懂的 我們還在建立感情階段
You know, we layin' down the groundwork right now.
知道搭肩膀這招嗎
You know about the shoulder touch?
當然知道
'Course I do.
不過  說來聽聽
But tell me anyway.
明天去找那姑娘 走到她面前  然後
Tomorrow, find that girl. You walk up to her and be like:
嘿
"Hey."
逗我呢嗎  艾倫叔叔
You serious, Uncle Aaron?
告訴你 這招很有技術含量的
I'm tellin' you, man, it's science.
走到她面前  然後說 嘿
So walk up to her and be like: "Hey."
不 不 不 應該是 嘿
No, no, no, no. Like: "Hey."
嘿
"Hey."
不 嘿
No. "Hey."
嘿
"Hey."
你真是我親侄子嗎
You sure you my nephew, man?
是她嗎
Is that her?
我該走了 還有一篇論文要寫
I should probably go. Still got a paper to do tonight.
居然不給我看你的新作  畫牆上了嗎
Yo, you been holdin' out on me? You throw these up yet?
沒有 別提了 你知道我爸的  沒戲
Naw, man. You know my dad. I can't.
來吧 我帶你去個好地方
Come on. I got a spot you ain't gon' believe.
不行 不行
Naw, I can't. I can't. Can't.
我會有麻煩的
I'm gonna get in so much trouble.
別怕 告訴你爸是美術老師讓的
Hey, man. Tell him your art teacher made you.
你怎麼會知道這個地方
How'd you know about this place?
我在這裏做過工程
Did an engineering job down here.
♪ One, two, three Four, five... ♪
怎麼了
What's up?
好吧  看來你是我親侄子
Yeah, man, I knew we were related.
Whoa!
布魯克林
Brooklyn!
這些牆上有很多歷史
There's a lot of history on these walls.
這地方太酷了
This is so fresh.
現在看你的了  邁爾斯
And now you on your own, Miles.
悠著點
Whoa, slow down a little.
很好
That's better.
♪ Who's the black sheep? What's the black sheep? ♪
♪ Don't know who I am When I'm coming so you sleep ♪
看到沒  畫錯也是其中一部分
See what you got now? Makin' mistakes is part of it.
♪ And you can't beat that... ♪
這才是真正的邁爾斯
The real Miles comin' outta hidin'.
♪ You gotta hay? It's for the hoes ♪
好了  你還可以用其他顏色來勾線
Now you can cut that line with another color.
♪ You can get with this Or you can get with that ♪
♪ You can get with this or You can get with that ♪
♪ I think you'll get with this For this is where it's at ♪
幫個忙
Little help?
♪ ...who was quite contrary Talkin' 'bout Mary... ♪
想要滴墨效果嗎 這樣也挺酷
Did you want drips? 'Cause if you do, that's cool,
但如果不是  你就得不停地移動
but if you don't, you gotta keep it moving.
要的就是這種效果
That's intentional.
是不是太瘋了
- Wow. - Is it too crazy?
怎麼會
No, man.
我知道你想表達什麼
Miles, I see exactly what you're doing there.
沒錯
Yeah. You know,
我和你爸以前也經常這麼干
me and your dad used to do this back in the day.
-別騙人了  -是真的
- Stop lyin'. - It's true.
有天他當了警察 怎麼說呢
Then he took on the cop thing, and I don't know...
他是個好人 只是
He's a good guy, just...
你懂我的意思
You know what I'm sayin'.
好了 走吧 夥計 我還有事
All right, come on, man. I gotta roll.
邁爾斯 快走
Miles, let's go.
真是詭異
That's weird.
褲子變短了
My pants shrank.
我想我發育了
I think I hit puberty.
我得買新褲子了
I gotta get new pants.
等等  為什麼我腦子裏的聲音這麼大
Wait. Why is the voice in my head so loud?
怎麼回事
What?
-你沒事吧 -什麼
- Oh! Are you okay? - What?
我為什麼會出這麼多的汗
Why am I so sweaty?
你怎麼出那麼多的汗
Why are you so sweaty?
因為我在發育
It's a puberty thing.
我也不知道自己為什麼要這麼說  我沒有在發育
I don't know why I said that. I'm not going through puberty.
我是說  我已經成熟了
I did, but I'm done.
我現在是個男人了
I'm a man.
你也是新來的  對吧 這點我們一樣
So you're, like, new here, right? We got that in common.
沒錯  這是其中一點
Yeah. That's one thing.
很好  對 我叫邁爾斯
Cool. Yeah. I'm Miles.
我叫格溫達
I'm Gwe... anda.
等等  你叫格溫達
Wait, your name is Gwanda?
沒錯  非洲名 我是南非人
Yes, it's African. I'm South African.
我從小在這兒長大  所以沒口音
No accent though 'cause I was raised here.
快使出搭肩膀那招  趁她還沒走
Do the shoulder touch now before she walks away.
為什麼感覺這麼慌
Why is this so scary?
是我在做慢動作  還是就是這種感覺
Am I doing this in slow motion or does it just feel that way?
逗你的 我叫溫達 沒有格  開個玩笑
I'm kidding. It's Wanda. No "G." That's crazy. Heh.
嘿
Hey.
好吧  那麼
Okay, then.
我們回頭見
I'll see you around.
回見
Oh. See you.
-抱歉 -嘿
- Sorry. Um... - Hey.
-怪了 -放開我好嗎
- Oh, crap. - Can you let go, please?
-我做不到 -別亂動 沒關係
- I can't let go. - Ow! Ow! Calm down. It's fine.
-邁爾斯 放開 -我也想
- Miles, let go. - Workin' on it.
這都要怪青春期
It's just puberty.
我想你對青春期的定義有什麼誤解吧  放輕鬆
I don't think you know what puberty is. Just relax.
-好吧  我有個主意 -很好
- Okay, I have a plan. - Great.
-我要使勁扯啦 -這是個愚蠢的主意
- I'm gonna pull really hard. - That's a terrible plan.
-一 -別那麼做
- One. - Don't do this.
-二 -三
- Two. - Three!
很高興認識你
Nice to meet you?
很好 好到爆
Sure. Total pleasure.
沒人看到 沒關係
No one saw. It's okay.
沒人知道 沒人知道
No one knows, no one knows.
大家都知道了
Everyone knows.
大家都知道了 他們在嘲笑我
Everyone knows. They're talkin' 'bout me.
他們都看到了
They saw everything!
他知道 她知道 他們都知道了
He knows. She knows. They know.
她長的可真高
Wow, she's super tall.
他為什麼在笑 我現在成怪胎了嗎
Why is he smiling? Am I the weird guy now?
我在幹嘛
What am I doing?
那傢伙真是個怪胎
That guy's such a weirdo.
我怎麼停下來
How do I stop?
他們能聽到我的心聲
Can they hear my thoughts?!
我的心聲怎麼會那麼大聲
Why are all my thoughts so loud?!
嘿 我知道你昨晚溜出去了 莫拉萊斯
Hey! I know you snuck out last night, Morales.
裝傻
Play dumb!
誰是莫拉萊斯
Who's Morales?
也別那麼傻
Not that dumb!
嘿
Hey!
好了 好了 沒事了
Okay, okay. You're okay.
沒事了
You're okay.
他找不到你的
He'll never find you.
不是吧
No.
Ow!
你在我辦公室裏做什麼 莫拉萊斯
What are you doing in my office, Morales?!
莫拉萊斯 快開門
Morales! Open up!
♪ Oh, Spider-bells Goblin smells ♪
為什麼會這樣
Why is this happening?
♪ Spider-buggy blew a tire ♪
我孩子愛聽這個
He's got a nice voice.
♪ Spidey-bells, Spidey-bells ♪
快開門
Open up!
別在粘著了
Stop sticking!
千萬別鬆開 邁爾斯
Keep sticking, Miles! Oh!
霍夫施塔特提出了
Hofstadter is suggesting...
他提出了
...is that we...
我們都應該
...look on the...
好吧
Okay.
我的房間
My room!
為什麼會這樣
"Why is this happening?"
別在粘著了
"Please stop sticking."
千萬別鬆開
"Please keep st..."
等等
Wait, wait, wait.
怎麼可能有兩個蜘蛛俠
How could there be two Spider-Men?
不可能有兩個蜘蛛俠
There can't be two Spider-Men.
可能嗎
Can there?
拜託  艾倫叔叔 快接電話
Come on, Uncle Aaron, pick up. Pick up!
我是艾倫
Yo, it's Aaron.
我要出城幾天
I'm outta town for a few days.
回來再打給你 再見
I'll hit you when I'm back. Peace.
不 不
No. No-No-No-No-No.
這不可能
It's not possible!
我只是在發育
It's just puberty.
那是只普通的蜘蛛 我是個普通的男孩
It's a normal spider and I'm a normal kid!
精彩
All right!
我得找人聊聊
I gotta tell someone.
是你想多了 邁爾斯 你想多了
Okay, you're being crazy, Miles. You're being crazy.
找到那只蜘蛛
Find the spider.
一切就清楚了
You'll see.
只是個普通蜘蛛
It's a normal spider.
感覺  簡直  普通的不能在普通了
It's, like, boring how normal this spider is.
在那邊
I'm right here.
為什麼偏偏是我
Why is this happening to me?
慢點 我這是怎麼了
Slow down! What am I doing?
在那邊
Way over there.
你就和我一樣
You're like me.
邁爾斯 小心
Miles. Look out.
我不想成為英雄
I don't wanna be a hero.
邁爾斯
Miles.
Whoa!
諾曼 你聽我說
Norman, listen to me.
蜘蛛俠
Spider-Man?
我不能讓你打開通往另一個時空的大門
I cannot let you open a portal to another dimension.
布魯克林承受不了這個
Brooklyn is not zoned for that.
這不由我決定
It's not up to me.
那是綠惡魔嗎
Is that Green Goblin?!
你為什麼不能放棄
Why won't you quit?!
因為我不想布魯克林被黑洞吞噬
I guess I like Brooklyn not being sucked into a black hole.
我想 我還是快跑吧
I think I'm gonna go.
斯塔頓島可以  反正布魯克林不行
Staten Island, maybe. Not Brooklyn.
不 不
No! No!
Whoa!
怎麼辦
What now?
這是什麼地方
What is this place?
知不知道你鞋帶鬆了
Did you know your shoes are untied?
我穿的是連體服
- Uh-huh. - This is a onesie,
所以不用擔心
so I don't really have to worry about it.
我以為我是唯一的 你和我一樣
I thought I was the only one. You're like me.
我可不想
I don't wanna be.
恐怕你沒有的選 孩子
I don't think you have a choice, kiddo.
我能理解你的困惑 相信我
Got a lot going through your head, I'm sure.
當然
Yeah.
你不會有事的 我可以幫你
You're gonna be fine. I can help you.
你等我一下  一會兒我會教你兩招
If you stick around, I can show you the ropes.
好的
Yeah.
我必須得趕在時空連續體崩塌
I just need to destroy this big machine real quick
之前毀掉那台機器
before the space-time continuum collapses.
別走開
Don't move.
一會見
See you in a bit.
他是怎麼做到的
How does he do that?
是在這嗎 不 是這
Is it here? No, no, it's here.
好了 各位
All right, folks.
派對結束
I always get this wrong.
糟糕
Oh, boy.
徘徊者
Prowler.
夥計 我正忙著呢
Man, I was in the middle of something.
心好累
I am so tired.
你在生我氣嗎 我覺得你是在生我氣
Are you mad at me? I feel like you're mad at me.
就這點能耐
That all you got?
真噁心
Aw, so gross.
我應該上去幫他
I should go up there and help him.
開什麼玩笑 這怎麼可能
Who am I kidding? I should not do that.
注意 蜘蛛俠來了
Watch out. Here comes the Spider-Man.
喜歡我的新玩具嗎
You like my new toy?
花了我不少錢呢  不過 錢乃身外之物
Cost me a fortune, but, hey, can't take it with you, right?
你大老遠過來 觀看我的試驗
You came all this way. Watch the test.
這會是場超炫的燈光秀
It's a hell of a freaking light show.
你一定會喜歡的
You're gonna love this.
不 別這樣 快停下
No! No, don't do this! Stop!
你不知道它能做什麼  你會害死我們的
You don't know what it can do! You'll kill us all!
我看到了多個宇宙正在開啟
I see multiple dimensions opening!
三個 四個 五個 不同的宇宙
That was three, four and five separate dimensions.
它們很不穩定 得馬上停下來
It's unstable! We should stop.
諾曼 你一般怎麼處理頭部創傷
Norm, what's your take on head trauma?
我都提醒你了
I tried to warn you, pal.
綠惡魔 不 把他弄出去
Goblin, no! Get him outta there!
威爾遜 我們在哪裏
Wilson! Where are we?
好奇怪
Really weird.
威爾遜
Wilson!
嘿  你沒事吧
Hey! Are you okay?
我沒事 我沒事 只是需要休息一下
I'm fine, I'm fine. I'm just resting.
-還能站起來嗎 -當然
- Can't you get up? - Yeah.
我每次都能站起來
Yeah, I always get up.
咳嗽可能不是個好兆頭
The coughing's probably not a good sign.
找到他 快
Find him. Now.
聽著 我們得合作 時間不多了
Listen, we gotta team up here. We don't have that much time.
只有這把重載鑰匙能阻止對撞機
This override key is the only way to stop the collider.
蕩過去 用這把鑰匙 摁下紅色按鈕 炸飛它
Swing up there, use this key, push the button and blow it up.
你得把臉藏起來
You need to hide your face.
別告訴任何人你是誰
You don't tell anyone who you are.
誰都不能說 他能撬開任何人得嘴
No one can know. He's got everyone in his pocket.
如果他再次啟動機器
If he turns the machine on again,
你所知道的一切都會消失
everything you know will disappear.
你的家人  所有人
Your family, everyone.
所有人
Everyone.
答應我好嗎
Promise me you'll do this.
我答應你
I promise.
去吧  毀了對撞機
Go. Destroy the collider.
我會去找你的
I'll come and find you.
不會有事的
It's gonna be okay.
墓碑
Tombstone.
試驗到此結束
We're done with tests.
盡快準備好再啟動一次
Get that thing ready to go again. And soon.
快跑
Run faster!
這群傢伙真沒用
These guys are weak.
本想說很高興又見到你了 蜘蛛俠
I'd say it's nice to see you again, Spider-Man,
可惜不是
but it's not.
嘿 金並 生意好嗎
Hey, Kingpin. How's business?
很火爆
Boomin'. Heh.
好吧 這樣可不行
Nice. Aw, that's a no-no.
你這麼做會在布魯克林的下面撕開一個黑洞
This might open a black hole under Brooklyn.
不能冒這個險
It can't be worth the risk.
不是所有事都是為了錢 蜘蛛俠
It's not always about the money, Spider-Man.
你不想知道我看到了什麼嗎
Don't you wanna know what I saw in there?
等等
Wait.
我知道你想幹什麼
I know what you're trying to do,
這麼做沒用的
and it won't work.
他們已經死了
They're gone.
把屍體處理掉
Get rid of the body.
誰在哪裏
What was that?
殺了他
Kill that guy.
別粘著了
Stop sticking!
請勿依靠車門 謝謝
Stand clear of the closing doors, please.
應該是班克斯風格的街頭藝術
Yeah, I think it's a Banksy.
警察 把手舉起來
Police! Put your hands up!
邁爾斯 邁爾斯
Miles? Miles?
你怎麼不在學校
Why aren't you at school?
怎麼了 沒事了 沒事了
Whoa, whoa, whoa. It's okay. It's okay.
邁爾斯 出什麼事了
Miles? ¿Que te pasa?
是因為地震嗎
Is it the earthquake?
我今晚能留下嗎
Can I sleep here tonight?
邁爾斯 今天不是週末
Miles. It's a weeknight.
你應該待在學校的
You made a commitment to that school.
他不舒服
He's upset.
你當然能留下
Of course you can stay.
-爸爸 -怎麼
- Dad? - Yeah.
你真的很討厭蜘蛛俠嗎
Do you really hate Spider-Man?
是吧  我是說 身為一名警察
Yeah. I mean, with a vigilante, there is...
傑弗森 親愛的
Jeff, mi amor.
怎麼了 是他問我的
What? He asked me.
你知道我對蜘蛛俠的看法
Baby, you know how I feel about Spider-Man. Come on.
你知道他很愛你
Tu sabes que el te quiere mucho.
所以才會這麼嚴格 你懂的對吧
That's why he's tough on you. You know that, right?
媽媽 你有沒有想過離開布魯克林
Mom, do you ever think about moving out of Brooklyn?
我們家的人從不逃避問題 邁爾斯
Our family doesn't run from things, Miles.
對 我知道
Yeah, I know.
到底怎麼回事
What's that about?
她正處於艱難期 傑夫
He's having a hard time, Jeff.
越是艱難
When it gets hard,
他越是應該堅持 你應該更溫柔一點
that's when he's gotta stick it out.
插播一條特別消息
We interrupt this broadcast for a special report.
一則悲痛的消息
Sad news tonight.
我們的英雄蜘蛛俠 今天離開了我們
The hero known as Spider-Man has died
他的死與今天發生在布魯克林的
after injuries related to another powerful earthquake
另一場神秘地震事件有關
in Brooklyn. Multiple sources are confirming
經多方消息證實 彼得 帕克
that Peter Parker, a 26-year-old grad student
26歲的研究生 兼職攝影師
and part-time photographer
在近十多年中 一直扮演著蜘蛛俠的角色
operated as Spider-Man for at least a decade.
♪ I'm not runnin' Runnin', runnin' ♪
♪ No, I'm not afraid Of the fall ♪
♪ I'm not scared... ♪
帕克家中還有他的妻子瑪麗 簡
He is survived by his wife, Mary Jane,
和他的嬸嬸梅 帕克
and his aunt, May Parker.
我們的英雄 蜘蛛俠 離開了我們
Our hero, Spider-Man, is gone.
♪ I'm not scared... ♪
我的丈夫 彼得 帕克
My husband, Peter Parker,
他曾是一個普通人
was an ordinary person.
他總是說誰都能成為面具後面的那個人
He always said it could've been anyone behind the mask.
他只是湊巧被蜘蛛咬了而已
He was just the kid who happened to get bit.
我會想念他的
I'm going to miss him.
是啊
Yeah.
我們以前可是朋友
We were friends, you know.
如果不合身 我能來退嗎
Can I return it if it doesn't fit?
到最後
It always fits
總會合身的
eventually.
這並不是他的本意
He didn't ask for his powers,
可他選擇成為了蜘蛛俠
but he chose to be Spider-Man.
我最愛彼得的地方就是
My favorite thing about Peter
他讓我們所有人都充滿了力量
is that he made us each feel powerful.
我們每個人都有著屬於自己的力量
We all have powers of one kind or another.
♪ Of the dark... ♪
我們以自己的方式
But in our own way.
扮演者蜘蛛俠
We are all Spider-Man.
我們需要你
And we're all counting on you.
他們需要我
They're counting on me.
應該不是特指你 只是個比喻而已
Probably not you specifically. I think it's a metaphor.
我很抱歉 帕克先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Parker.
你給我的那把重載鑰匙
That thing you gave me, that key
我可能把它弄壞了
I think I really messed it up.
我也想遵守約定
I wanna do what you asked.
I really do.
對不起
But I'm sorry.
沒有你
I'm not sure I'm the guy.
我一個人根本不行
I can't do this without you.
嘿 孩子
Hey, kid.
Whoa!
我對他做了什麼
What did I do to him?!
不
No.
你是誰
Who are you?
好吧 各位 我們最後再來一次
All right, people, let's do this one last time.
我叫彼得 班傑明 帕克
My name is Peter B. Parker.
我被一隻受過輻射的蜘蛛咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
在接下來的二十二年裏
And for the last 22 years,
我以為我是這世上唯一的蜘蛛俠
I thought I was the one and only Spider-Man.
忙碌的一天
What a day.
剩下的你們肯定都知道了
I'm pretty sure you know the rest.
我救過這座城市  墜入過愛河 還結了婚
You see, I saved the city, fell in love, I got married,
又救了幾次城市 或許太多次了
saved the city some more, maybe too much.
我的婚姻出現了危機  投資了一些糟糕的項目
My marriage got testy, made some dicey money choices.
千萬別投以蜘蛛俠為名的主題餐廳
Don't invest in a spider-themed restaurant.
就這樣過去了15年 吧啦 吧啦 吧啦
Then like 15 years passed. Blah, blah, blah. Super boring.
超級無聊 我摔斷了背脊  臉撞在了無人機上
I broke my back, a drone flew into my face,
送走了梅嬸嬸
I buried Aunt May.
最後和我的妻子分開了
My wife and I split up.
但這一切我都沉著以對
But I handled it like a champion.
你知道嗎
'Cause, you know what,
因為不管遭受多少次打擊
no matter how many times I get hit,
我最終總是會爬起來的
I always get back up.
我有大把的時間自我反省
And I got a lot of time to reflect and work on myself.
你知道嗎 海馬一旦結合 就再也不會分開了
Did you know that seahorses, that they mate for life?
你能想像嗎
Could you imagine?
一隻海馬 見到了另一隻海馬
A seahorse seeing another seahorse
然後他們就成了
and then making it work?
她想要孩子 可是
She wanted kids and...
這嚇壞我了
And it scared me.
我知道我傷心了她的心
I'm pretty sure I broke her heart.
閃進 當時我正在家裏做俯臥撐
Flash-forward: I'm in my apartment doing push-ups,
還有仰臥起坐 讓自己變得更強
doing ab crunches, getting strong,
突然奇怪的事發生了
when this weird thing happened.
雖然我對奇怪的事已經見慣不怪了
And I gotta say, weird things happen to me a lot.
可是 這次的情況真的很奇怪
But this was real weird.
Ow!
我還在紐約 可周圍不太一樣
You see, I was in New York, but things were different.
而且我死了
Also, I was dead.
還有一頭金髮
And blond.
我看起來簡直完美
I was kind of perfect.
感覺就像是在照鏡子一樣
It was like looking in a mirror.
我有種直覺
I have a feeling that the thing
帶我來到這裏的東西
that brought me here
就是害死他的原因
was the thing that got him killed.
想知道接下來發生了什麼
You wanna know what happened next?
我也想知道
Me, too.
你是誰
Who are you?
你在哪裏幹嘛
What are you doin' over there?
別動 紐約警察
Freeze! P.D.N.Y.
站住
Stop!
這是在逗我呢嗎
Are you kidding me right now?
站住 站住
Stop! Stop!
我帶你走 我帶你走
I gotcha. I gotcha.
嘿 小子 放小屍體
Hey, kid. Drop the body.
-嘿 小子 快過來 -別跑
- Hey, kid. Get over here! - Come on, now!
Whoa.
回頭見 警官
See you, officers!
不是吧
Aw, come on.
-嘿 小子 -別亂動
- Hey, kid. - Kid, come on, now!
舉起手 孩子
Put 'em up, son!
再見
Uh... adios?
救命 快讓火車停下
Help! Somebody stop that train!
嘿 什麼情況
Oh, hey. What the...?
抱歉
Sorry.
要死翹翹啦
I'm gonna die!
情況好像是 一個打扮成蜘蛛俠的孩子
Looks like a child dressed like Spider-Man
拖著一個流浪漢的屍體在追火車
dragging a homeless corpse behind a train.
太好了 我沒殺了你
Yes! I didn't kill you.
-你是誰 -你又是誰
- Who are you? - Who are you?
你為什麼想要殺我
Why are you trying to kill me?
我沒有 我是想要救你
I'm not. I'm trying to save you.
麻煩繞道走好嗎
Hey, maybe you guys can go around?
好吧 謝謝配合
All right. Thanks, New York.
什麼情況
What was that?
那孩子電擊了我
Kid electrocuted me
用他的手嗎
with his hands.
-你和我一樣 -我有話要問你
- You're like me. - I got some questions.
你為什麼那麼像彼得 帕克
Why do you look like Peter Parker?
因為我就是彼得 帕克
Because I am Peter Parker.
那你怎麼沒死 頭髮也不一樣了
Then why aren't you dead? And why is your hair different?
為什麼你變老了 還有你的體型
Why are you older? And why is your body
怎麼變形了
a different shape?
你是想說我胖是吧
Pretty sure you just called me fat.
你也沒帥到哪裏去 小子
You don't look so hot either, kid.
超級英雄不會買自己的周邊
Most superheroes don't wear their own merch.
-你是鬼魂嗎 -不是
- Are you a ghost? - No.
-你是殭屍嗎  -你話太多了
- Are you a zombie? - Stop it.
-我是殭屍嗎 =別扯淡了
- Am I a zombie? - You're not even close.
你來自另一個時空 就像平行宇宙
Are you from another dimension? Like a parallel universe
彼此相似但卻又不相同
where things are like this universe but different?
你是哪裏的蜘蛛俠
And you're Spider-Man in that universe?
然後你穿越到了這裏
But somehow traveled to this universe,
而你並不知道原因
but you don't know how?
你真的只是隨便猜猜的
Wow. That was really just a guess?
其實 我們在物理課上學過
We learned about it in physics.
-量子理論 -這太酷了
- Quantum theory. - This is amazing!
那你就可以像彼得 帕克說的那樣教我了
You can teach me like Peter said he would.
在他生前
Before he died.
-對 沒錯 -好吧
- Yeah. Exactly. - Yeah, right.
聽著 我答應過他的
Look, I made a promise to him.
我現在就來教你第一課 小子
Here's lesson number one, kid.
別光顧著聽 要仔細看
Don't watch the mouth. Watch the hands.
彼特 我是認真的
Peter, seriously...
相信我 孩子
Trust me, kid.
這樣你會過的輕鬆一點
This'll all make you a better Spider-Man.
嘿 你還好嗎
Hey, are you okay?
不 很不好
No, I'm not.
你的身體怎麼了
What's going on with your body?
我的原子可能
I don't think my atoms are real jazzed
不太適應這個錯誤的時空
about being in the wrong dimension.
聽著 我不是來應聘兼職
Look, I'm not looking for a side gig
做蜘蛛俠教練的
as a Spider-Man coach.
在我的世界我還有很多事前要處理
I got a lot going on in my dimension.
能力越大 責任就
"With great power comes great..."
別在我面前說那句話
Don't you dare finish that sentence.
別再說了 我受夠了
Don't do it! I'm sick of it.
想要我的意見 做回普通小孩吧
Want my advice? Go back to being a regular kid.
我根本沒得選
I don't have a choice!
金並造了一架對撞機
Kingpin's got a supercollider.
他想要殺了我
He's tryin' to kill me.
-你剛才說什麼 -金並想要殺了我
- What did you just say? - Kingpin's tryin' to kill me.
誰關心這個 對撞機在哪裏
Who cares about that. Where's the collider?
布魯克林 菲斯克大樓下面
Brooklyn. Under Fisk Tower.
-再見  -你要去哪裏
- Goodbye. - Where you going?
等它再啟動時 只要跳進去
When it runs again, I'll jump in
-就能回家了 -不能重啟對撞機
- and get back to my life. - You can't let them run it.
我的任務就是毀了它
I'm supposed to destroy it
阻止它再次啟動 否則所有人都會死
so it never runs again or everyone's gonna die.
否則所有人都會死  他們每次都愛說這句話
"Or everyone's gonna die." That is what they always say.
但在「所有人都會死」之前總還會有點時間
But there's always a little bit of time before everybody dies
這時就要看我的了
and that's when I do my best work.
你難道不需要這個嗎
Aren't you gonna need this?
你有個小玩意啊  交給我
Aw, you have a goober. Give it.
等等 不 沒那麼容易 他管它叫重載鑰匙
Wait, no. Not so fast. He called it an override key.
總會有把漏洞鑰匙 病毒鑰匙  各種亂七八糟的鑰匙
There's always a bypass key, a virus key, a who-cares key.
記都記不清
I can never remember,
所以索性叫它們小玩意  交給我
so I always call it a goober. Give it.
我需要它幫我摧毀對撞機
I need it to destroy the collider.
我需要它幫我回家
I need it to go home.
不行 再逼我 我就吞了它
I'll swallow it. Don't play with me.
-什麼 -我說
- What? - I said...
對撞機打開了入口 把我帶到了這裏
The collider created a portal that brought me here.
所以我得
And I have to get...
-你把它搞壞了 -不 本來就是壞的
- Did you break this? - No, it broke.
我不記得發生了什麼
I don't remember what happened.
看到沒 所以我才不要孩子 簡直太明智了
See, this is why I never had kids.
我們不能再做一個嗎
Can't we make another one?
這裏沒有你什麼事  多虧了你
We can't do anything. Thanks to you,
我得重複那個傢伙的工作  去歐克馬克斯再偷一次數據
I have to re-steal what your guy stole from Alchemax
做一個新鑰匙
and make another one of these.
如果你走之後我沒能關掉對撞機
If I don't turn off the collider after you leave,
這座城市的每個人
everyone in this city,
我的父母 我的叔叔  成千上萬的人都會死
my parents, my uncle and millions of others, will die.
你打算就這麼一走了之
And you're just gonna go home
把我一個人留在這裏面對這一切
and leave me here to figure this out for myself?
-你做得出這種事嗎 蜘蛛俠 -我能
- You good with that, Spider-Man? - Yeah.
你蹲在哪裏幹嘛
What are you doing?
讓你良心不安  有效果嗎
Making you feel guilty. Is it working?
怎麼可能 不 你看我
How could it...? No. Look at me.
像有效果的樣子嗎
Does it look like it's working?
不 沒有 當然沒有
No. No, it's not...
不行 不能讓他得逞
No! No! No! Do not let him win!
好吧 孩子 你贏了
All right, kid. You win.
走吧 我們沒時間浪費了
Come on, we don't have a second to lose.
我超喜歡這漢堡 太好吃了
Mmm. I love this burger. So delicious.
我吃過的最好的漢堡之一
One of the best burgers I've ever had.
在我們哪裏 這地方六年前就關門了
In my universe, this place closed six years ago.
真搞不懂 明明很好吃
I don't know why. I really don't.
Mmm.
你帶錢了對吧 我最近手頭有點緊
You have money, right? I'm not very liquid right now.
-說正經事好嗎  -當然
- Can we focus? - Mm-hm. Sure.
-另一個彼得 -你不吃嗎
- The other Peter... - You gonna eat that?
我在聽呢
I'm listening.
另一個彼得之前
The other Peter said he was gonna be
說過他會教我幾招
- showing me the ropes. - Wow.
你有什麼蜘蛛俠竅門可以教我嗎
You got any Spider-Man tips you can tell me now?
多了去了
Yeah, I got plenty.
面具要消毒
Disinfect the mask.
穿緊身衣要撲點爽身粉
You're gonna wanna use baby powder in the suit,
尤其事關節部分
heavy on the joints.
你也不想出疹子 對吧
You don't want any chafing, right?
-還有別的嗎 -沒了 就這些
- Anything else? - Nope, that was everything.
你這老師也太差勁了吧
I think you're gonna be a bad teacher.
查查歐克馬克思在哪裏
Uh-uh-uh? Look up where Alchemax is.
紐約哈德遜山谷的一家私人科技園區
"A private technological campus in Hudson Valley, New York."
你可以教我
You can teach me
怎麼蕩過去
to swing on the way there.
我們不可能一路蕩到哈德遜山谷
I'm not swinging to the Hudson Valley, Miles.
尤其是吃了漢堡大餐之後
Not after a hearty burger breakfast.
節省點體力 你會感謝我的
Keep your legs fresh. You're gonna thank me later.
♪ I can see a new horizon ♪
♪ Underneath the blazing sky ♪
♪ I'll be where the eagle's Flying higher... ♪
-還有別穿斗篷 -我覺得還挺酷的
- And it's a no on the cape. - I think it's cool.
快脫掉 丟死人了
Take that off. It's disrespectful.
蜘蛛俠不穿斗篷
Spider-Man doesn't wear a cape.
我們要怎麼重複彼得的工作
So how do we retrace Peter's steps?
這是個好問題
That's a good question.
如果我是我 我會怎麼做
What would I do if I were me?
有了
Got it.
第一步 先潛入實驗室
I infiltrate the lab.
第二步 找到首席科學家的電腦
Find the head scientist's computer.
那位推自行車的女士就是
That lady with the bike is the head scientist.
我在學校的紀錄片裏見過她
I saw her in this documentary.
很好 第三步 暫時拋開性別歧視
Cool! Step Three: I reexamine my personal biases.
第四步 黑近她的電腦
I hack the computer.
其實也不算黑進去
It's not technically hacking.
應該是 行了 別打斷我的思路
Not now. I just lost my train of thought.
第五步 下載重要信息
Download the important stuff.
看到我就知道
I'll know it when I see it.
第六步 從餐廳抓一個麵包圈 然後拔腿就跑
I grab a bagel from the cafeteria and run.
那我要幹嘛
So, what am I doing?
第七步 你在這裏把風 非常重要
Step Seven: You stay here. You're lookout. Very important.
聽著 夥計 你得教我蜘蛛俠的技能
Look, man. You gotta teach me how to do Spider-Man stuff
這樣我才能幫你
or I won't be able to help.
好的 學著點 小子 一會兒我來考你
Watch and learn, kid! I'll quiz ya later!
為什麼我要和這個又老又矬的
Why did I get stuck with
流浪蜘蛛俠在一起
the janky, old, broke hobo Spider-Man?!
新技能
That's new.
金並
Kingpin.
我在幹嘛 我在幹嘛
What am I doing? What am I doing?
Whoa!
彼得
Peter!
-你在這裏幹嘛 -金並來了
- What are you doing here? - Kingpin's here.
你往邊上去點
Just move over.
你壓著我腳了 趕緊爬過去
You're steppin' on my foot. Go back outside.
不 我不能眼睜睜看著蜘蛛俠遇難
No! I can't sit there and let Spider-Man die
自己卻什麼都不做
without doing anything about it.
我不會再那麼做了
I'm not doing that again.
幹嘛
What?
我遇到的人大多都是想要殺了我的
Most people I meet in the workplace try to kill me,
所以換種畫風也不錯
so you're a nice change of pace.
菲斯克先生  請看數據
Mr. Fisk! Look at this data.
我知道你不理解
I know you can't really understand it,
但這些都是好消息
but these are really good numbers.
我知道密碼了
And I got the password.
菲斯克先生 如果本周再次重啟對撞機
Mr. Fisk. If we fire again this week
布魯克林的下面就會產生一個黑洞
there could be a black hole under Brooklyn.
你看這個 還有這個
You see this? And this?
這就是多重宇宙開始
This is multiple dimensions
相互擠壓得跡象
beginning to crash into each other.
這是蜘蛛俠劇情得老套路
This is pretty standard Spider-Man stakes.
要慢慢習慣 看好了
You get used to it. Watch this.
他會說  我再給你24小時
He's gonna say, "You've got 24 hours."
我再給你24小時
You've got 24 hours.
這麼做的話可能會導致
What this means is there could be a rupture
連續時空裏出現裂縫
in the space-time continuum.
太糟了
Ooh. That's bad.
其實她說的句句都很糟糕
Actually, everything she said was bad.
是我輕敵了
I was lying before.
好吧 等等 還有別的數據
Hold on. Let me get you some more data.
-你在幹嗎 夥計 -我動不了了
- What are you doing, bud? - I can't move.
好了 放鬆你的手指
Okay, relax your fingers.
我們沒時間了 放手 放掉就好  進入狀態
We don't have time. Just let go. Be in the moment.
我在狀態裏 而且是糟糕的狀態
I am in the moment. It's a terrible moment.
-我不是在拒絕 -別再找借口了
- I'm not refusing. - No more excuses.
我只是需要時間
I just need more time.
他們就在外面 你會被發現的
They're right there. They're gonna see you.
邁爾斯 你得趕緊鬆手
Miles, you gotta unstick.
你一般怎麼做才會放鬆
What do you do to relax?
放鬆 好的 好的
Relax. Okay, okay, okay.
無需多說 我已明瞭
♪ Needless to say, I... ♪
還有這種操作
Oh, for crying out loud.
如果現在放棄 寶貝 我承受不起
♪ Callin' it quits Now, baby, I'm a wreck ♪
♪ You're a wreck, ooh... ♪
小屁孩果然不靠譜
just the worst.
-邁爾斯 你去哪裏了 -我就在這裏
- Miles, where did you go? - I'm right here.
-在哪裏 我看不見你 -我就在你面前
- Where? I can't see ya. - I'm right in front of you.
-蜘蛛俠能隱身嗎 -在我們哪裏不行
- Can Spider-Man turn invisible? - Not in my universe.
你戳到我眼睛了
Aah! You just poked me in my eye!
真是不可思議 像是打不過就閃的本能
This is incredible. Some kind of fight or flight thing.
什麼意思
What's that?
把密碼記下來
Remember this password. D-G-F-A-M-P-E-S-A-N-D...
慢點
Slow down!
-4-$-3-5-8-7-6-5-3-4-5-4-5-3-5.
-我得寫下了 -接著下載設計圖
- I need to write it down! - Download the schematic.
-我要怎麼做 -然後看我使出美男計
- How do I do that? - While I turn on the charm.
蜘蛛俠
Spider-Man?
嘿 剛才沒看到你
Oh, hey. Didn't see you there.
Wow.
好吧 我有點被嚇著了
Okay, I'm kinda freaking out right now.
我是說 你應該死了才對
You're supposed to be dead.
沒想到吧  好吧 這樣可不行 我不習慣那樣
Surprise! Okay. That's a no-no. We don't like that.
真是太神奇了
This is fascinating.
好吧 那是我的臉
Okay, that's my face.
一個完全不同的彼得 帕克
An entirely different Peter Parker.
好吧 有點小肚腩 可能是因為空間扭曲
Little bit of a gut, perhaps from dimensional warping.
對 對 對 穿越前我比現在廋多了
Oh, yeah-yeah-yeah. I was way flatter before I warped.
穿越時空似乎
Travel through the multiverse
會造成細胞惡化
appears to have deteriorated the...
接下去是什麼
What was the rest?!
嘿 你多大了
Hey, how old are you?
你看上去不超過35
'Cause you don't look a day over 35.
他們都說我瘋了  他們說我瘋了
They said I was crazy! They said I was crazy!
告訴他們你沒有瘋
You showed 'em you're not crazy.
這可能會有點疼
This might pinch a little.
我知道 我只需要取一些樣本
I know. I just need to get these samples.
好吧
Okay.
就不能整理下桌面嗎 女士
Organize your desktop, lady.
體內的細胞正在發生衰變
Wow. Just complete cellular decay.
從來沒見過這種情況
I've never seen anything like this.
你在做什麼
What are you doing?
把數據連窩端走
I'm just taking the whole thing.
很明顯 你出故障了
And obviously you've been glitching.
故障 不 為什麼這麼說
"Glitchin'"? No. Why would you even say that?
你在這個空間待太久了
If you stay in this dimension too long,
你的身體正在瓦解
your body's gonna disintegrate.
知道這會有多疼嗎 彼得 帕克
Do you know how painful that would be, Peter Parker?
我不知道
I don't know.
你根本想像不到
You can't imagine.
而我迫不及待
And I, for one,
想要見證那一刻
can't wait to watch.
你叫什麼名字來著
What did you say your name was?
埃利維亞 奧克塔維厄斯博士
Dr. Olivia Octavius.
我猜你的朋友是不是都叫你章魚博士
Can I assume that your friends call you Doc Ock?
我朋友都叫我麗芙
My friends actually call me Liv.
我的敵人才叫我章魚博士
My enemies call me Doc Ock.
這交給我 快跑
I got this! Run!
你在和誰說話
Who are you talking to?
-我能搞定  -你搞得定嗎 彼得
- I got it! - Oh, you "Got it," Peter?
我穩得住 夥計
I got it handled, buddy!
一切盡在掌握
Everything is fine!
好吧 情況
Okay, this is
-有點失控 -你廢話還真多
- a little bit bad. - You're chatty.
快跑
Gotta go.
我想我快堅持不住了
This is the moment that I'm losin' the fight.
好吧 告訴你個好消息  我們不需要顯示器
Let me tell you the good news. We don't need the monitor.
彼得
Peter!
你怎麼沒告訴我你還有個會隱身的朋友
You didn't tell me you had an invisible friend!
把電腦給我好嗎 年輕人
Could you give me that back, young man?
彼得
Peter!
這是私人財產
It's proprietary.
Oh.
這種情況還是
This'd be a good time
-隱身比較好 -沒錯
- to turn invisible. - Yep.
好吧 那你怎麼還不隱身  挑一個麵包圈
Okay, not gonna turn invisible. Selecting a bagel.
表現得自然一點
Act super normal.
蜘蛛俠
Spider-Man?
說來你也不信
You know, that's funny,
-很多人都會認錯 -嘿
- I get that a lot. - Hey.
-蜘蛛俠  -嘿 舉起手
- Spider-Man? - Hey! Hands up!
好了 交換一下 什麼
Now we do a switchy-switchy.
給我回來
Get back here!
你們想去哪裏
Where do you think you're going?
-他偷了麵包圈 -準備好蕩起來
- He took a bagel! - Time to swing,
-就像我教你的那樣  -你什麼時候教過我
- just like I taught ya. - When did you teach me that?
也對 我只是開個玩笑 曾進感情
I didn't. It's a little joke for team-building.
嘿
Hey!
-準備好了嗎 -當然沒有
- All right, you ready? - Of course I'm not ready!
我還做不到
I can't do this yet!
大家都知道 一個人在生死關頭
Everybody knows that the best way to learn
可以做到許多本來做不到的事
is under intense life-threatening pressure.
拜託 拜託
Come on, come on, come on.
Uh-oh.
你在下面做什麼
What are you doing down there?
我跑的得比蕩的快
I run better than I swing.
你得蕩起來 不然他們會抓住你的
You gotta swing or they'll catch you.
這就是你想學的
This is what you wanted.
Uh-oh.
快回來 小傢伙
Come back, little boy.
以胯部為準線 瞄準目標位置
Aim with your hips! Look where you want it to hit.
肩膀放平 別忘了後續動作
Square your shoulders. Don't forget to follow through!
重心在後腳時不要發射
Don't shoot off your back foot.
-太多了記不住  -那就別管我說的
- That's too many things! - Then stop listening to me!
這是你今天給的最有用的建議
That's the best idea you've had all day!
漂亮 邁爾斯
Nice, Miles!
很好 你做到了
Good. You're doin' it.
輕按兩下鬆開 然後在發射一次
Double tap to release and thwip it out again.
發射 然後鬆開
Thwip and release.
-發射 鬆開  -發射 鬆開
- And thwip. Release. Thwip. - And release.
悟性不錯 發射 鬆開
You're a natural. Thwip. Release.
-找到節奏了嗎 -發射再鬆開
- Feel the rhythm? - Thwip. And release!
很不錯 邁爾斯
Good, Miles.
我想說 你超級酷的 夥計
I gotta say, you're amazing, man.
我們是團隊了
We're a little team!
我是實力不減當年的老師
Me as the teacher who could still do it.
你資質不錯 但和我當年比你還差點
You as the student who can do it, just not as good.
真為我們驕傲  你有什麼想對我說的嗎
I'm proud of us. Is there something you want to say to me?
彼得
Peter!
-搞什麼  -誰幹的
- What the...? - Who did that?
嘿 夥計們
Hey, guys.
格溫達
Gwanda?
是格溫才對
It's Gwen, actually.
你認識她 真是不錯
Oh, you know her. Very cool.
我來自另一個宇宙
I'm from another dimension.
我是說除了另一個還有一個
I mean, another-another dimension.
好吧 各位 我們再從頭來一次
All right, people. Let's start at the beginning one last time.
我叫格溫 史黛西
My name is Gwen Stacy.
我被一隻受過輻射的蜘蛛咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
在接下的兩年裏
And for the last two years,
我成為了唯一的女蜘蛛俠
I've been the one and only Spider-Woman.
剩下的你們都知道了
You guys know the rest.
我加入了樂隊
I joined a band.
救了我爸爸
Saved my dad.
可是卻沒能救下我最好的朋友
I couldn't save my best friend,
彼得 帕克
Peter Parker,
所以我發誓要救其他人
so now I save everyone else.
於是我決定再也不交朋友了
And I don't do friends anymore,
避免一切干擾
just to avoid any distractions.
突然有一天 奇怪的事發生了
And one day this weird thing happened.
這次的情況真的很奇怪
And I mean, like, really weird.
我穿越到了上個星期
I was blown into last week.
一點都不誇張
Literally.
我回到了紐約 可不是我的紐約
I landed in New York, but not my New York.
幸運的是
Lucky for these folks,
蜘蛛俠出現了
Spider-Man was there to save the day.
我的蜘蛛直覺告訴我得去願景學校
My Spider-sense told me to head to Visions Academy.
是你們早到了
...you guys are early.
我也不知道為什麼 知道遇上了你
Wasn't sure why until I met you.
Oh!
我喜歡你的髮型
I like your haircut.
你還好意思說
You don't get to like my haircut.
我們走
Let's go.
到底有多少蜘蛛俠
How many more Spider-People are there?
自己去動漫展上看把
Save it for Comic-Con.
動漫展是什麼
What's Comic-Con? Whoa!
受死吧 蜘蛛俠
You're dead, Spider-Man.
威爾遜 你在做什麼
Wilson! What are you doing?
瓦娜沙
Vanessa.
理查德 快走
Richard, come on.
瓦娜沙 理查德
Vanessa! Richard!
不
No!
別往後看 親愛的  沒事的 沒事的
Don't look back, honey. It's okay. It's okay.
我明明殺了蜘蛛俠
I killed Spider-Man.
為什麼又多出來兩個
Why did I just see two more?
準確的說是三個
There's three, actually.
這是好事 非常非常好
No, this is good. This is very, very good.
這意味著你的目的達到了
This means you get what you want.
我的對撞機起作用了
It means my collider works.
現在我們要做的就是滅掉那幾隻蜘蛛
All we have to do is kill a couple of Spiders.
然後你的家人就能回到你的身邊
And the collider will bring your family back.
想要多少就有多少
As many families as you want.
明天啟動我的對撞機
Tomorrow, at my collider.
是我們的對撞機
Our collider.
是他弄壞的嗎
He broke this?
對 他也覺得很不好意思
Yeah. He's actually really embarrassed about it,
所以就當沒這回事好嗎
so just keep it between us, okay?
我知道哪裏能做個新的
I know where we can make a new one.
這次不會再讓他弄壞了
And we won't let him break it this time.
你朋友的事我很遺憾
I'm sorry about your friend.
謝謝你 邁爾斯
Thanks, Miles.
我知道這有多艱難
I know how hard this is.
要一個人面對這一切
To have to figure this stuff out on your own.
知道自己不是一個人感覺還不錯
It's kinda nice not being the only Spider-person around.
是啊
Yeah.
如果哪天你願意交朋友了
If you ever decide to do friends again,
我可以給你留個位置
I could always open up a slot.
到時候我會告訴你的
I'll keep you posted.
好的
Cool.
不如我們還是走吧
We should probably go.
彼得 都已經到門口了
Peter, we're literally on the doorstep.
太糟了 這主意太遭了
Bad idea. This is a bad idea.
放輕鬆
Just relax.
感謝你們的關心
You guys are all very sweet,
但今天不接待粉絲了 謝謝
but no more fans today, please.
我還沒心理準備
I'm not ready for this.
彼得
Peter?
嘿 梅嬸嬸
Hey, Aunt May.
我知道這聽起來有些瘋狂
So this is gonna sound crazy,
不過 我其實是來自
but I'm pretty sure that I'm from an...
另一個時空
An alternate dimension.
沒錯
Yeah.
你看起來很累 彼得
You look tired, Peter.
好吧 確實很累
Well, I am tired.
-有點蒼老 而且還豐滿了  -對 已經有人說了
- And older. And thicker. - Yeah. I've heard that already.
天啊 這個是寬鬆褲嗎
Oh, jeez. Are those sweatpants?
沒錯 就是寬鬆褲
Yup, that's what they are.
彼得走的時候
I was there,
我就在現場
when it all happened.
我真的很抱歉
I am so sorry.
你又是從哪個空間來的
And what dimension are you from?
布魯克林
Brooklyn.
彼得有沒有什麼地方能讓我們重做一下這個
Did Peter have a place where we could make another one of these?
是小玩意
A goober.
跟我來
Follow me.
好吧 我也有這麼個地方
Oh, yeah, I got one of these, too.
存放裝備的小屋子
A little, old shed where I keep my Spider-gear.
這地方也太能裝了
I mean, this place is pretentious.
Whoa.
夥計 你那裏也和這裏一樣
Dude. Was yours anything like this?
差不多吧
Mine was like this,
不過沒有吉普和飛機
but take away the jeep, the plane.
想像一下是這的縮小版 再多個床墊
Imagine it way smaller. Imagine a futon.
現在的年輕人真是的
I feel sad for this guy.
嘿 彼得
Hey, Peter.
這不是斗篷嗎
I think this is a cape.
彼得知道他的使命有多危險
Peter knew how dangerous the job was.
可他也知道這世上唯一能阻止那傢伙的
But he figured the only one who could stop this guy
只有蜘蛛俠
was Spider-Man.
金並知道我們會去找他
Kingpin knows we're coming.
可惜我們寡不敵眾
We're going to be outnumbered.
那可不一定
Don't be so sure.
你們可能會用到這個
You might need these.
你們以為只有你們想到要來這裏嗎
You think you're the only people who thought to come here?
嘿 夥計們
Hey, fellas.
他是黑白的嗎
Is he in black and white?
哪裏來的風 這裏可是地下室
Where's that wind coming from? We're in a basement.
不管到哪裏 冷風總是相隨
Wherever I go, the wind follows.
而這風 終將幻化成雨
And the wind, it smells like rain.
大家好
Hi, guys!
你們好嗎 很高興認識你們
This could literally not get any weirder.
敢不敢再詭異一點
It can get weirder.
我剛洗了手 所以它才是濕的
I just washed my hands. That's why they're wet.
沒別的原因
No other reason.
你們和我一樣
You're like me.
我叫彼得 帕克
My name is Peter Parker.
我叫潘妮 帕克
My name is Peni Parker.
我叫彼得 波克
My name is Peter Porker.
我被一隻受過輻射的蜘蛛(豬)咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
在我的宇宙 現在是1933年
In my universe, it's 1933,
我是名私家偵探
and I'm a private eye.
我愛喝布魯克林特飲 蛋密乳
I like to drink egg creams,
也喜歡打擊納粹 非常喜歡
and I like to fight Nazis. A lot.
我來自3145年的紐約
I'm from New York in the year 3145.
我爸的機器人裏住著一隻蜘蛛
I have a psychic link with a spider
我和它有心靈感應
who lives inside my father's robot.
我們是一輩子的好朋友
And we're best friends. Forever.
有時我會讓火柴一直燃燒到指尖
Sometimes I let matches burn down to my fingertips
只是為了能有點感覺
just to feel something, anything.
我是嗥叫日報
I'm a photographer
的攝影師
for the Daily Beagle.
工作時間
When I'm not pooching around,
我會像狗狗一樣
I'm working like a dog,
到處挖掘勁爆新聞
trying to sniff out the latest story.
我唱歌 我跳舞
♪ I frolic and I dance ♪
我邊跳邊扭屁股
♪ And I do this With my pants ♪
好了 可以了
Okay! Enough!
那麼 你們是怎麼來的
So how did you get here?
好吧 這可就說來話長了
Well, it's kind of a long story.
或許也沒那麼長
Maybe not that long.
現在 我們只想回家
And now we're just trying to find a way home.
回家的唯一方法就是跳進那個對撞機
The only way home is back through that collider gizmo.
唯一的問題就是
The only trouble is...
得有個人留下來毀了那機器
One of us has to stay behind and destroy it.
我留下來
- I'll do it. - I'll do it. - I'll do it.
不 你們不明白
No, no, no. You guys don't get it.
不明白什麼
Don't get what?
你們不能留在這裏  留在這裏 你們會死的
None of you can stay here. If you stay here, you'll die.
應該由我來關掉那機器
I'm the guy who's gonna turn it off.
我會等你們都會之後再動手
And I'm gonna get you all home before I do.
我答應過他的 所以我必須做到
Look, I made a promise. So I have to keep it.
你是哪位
Who are you again?
他是邁爾斯
This is Miles.
他將會拯救平行宇宙
And he's gonna save the multiverse.
對 沒錯
Yeah, man.
這小子會隱身術
This kid can turn himself invisible.
看好了  他現在就能隱身
Watch this. He can do it now.
-我不能說隱身就隱身  -他不能說隱身就隱身
- I can't do it on command. - He can't do it on command.
但還是很酷  讓他們看看電擊 邁爾斯
But it is cool. Show 'em the zappy thing, Miles.
-我不能說來就來 -他不能說來就來
- Can't do it on command. - He can't do it on command.
但他還有其他技能  比如什麼來著
But he can do so much more. What else do you do?
只有這兩樣
- Just those two things. - Just those two things.
夥計
Aw, man.
聽著 我見過他的技能 他很有潛力
Look, I've seen him in action. He's got potential.
我想他能送我們回家
I think he's gonna get us home.
好吧 年輕人
Okay, little fella,
金並會派很多壞蛋去找你
Kingpin's gonna send a lot of mugs after ya.
各個都很難纏 真正的大塊頭
I'm talkin' hard boys, real biscuit boxers.
你能一次性搞定他們嗎
Can you fight them all off at once?
其實我還沒有和別人交過手
I haven't actually fought anyone.
出其不意
Surprise attack!
你能在交火時重新組裝主機嗎
Can you rewire a mainframe while being shot at?
-你說什麼 -讓我看看
- Can I what? - Show me!
出其不意
Surprise attack!
你能像舞蹈家那樣優雅地在半空迴盪嗎
Can you swing and flip with the grace of a trained dancer?
你能切斷自己的人性
Can you close off your feelings so you don't get crippled
不為自己的暴力行為而感到內疚嗎
by the moral ambiguity of your violent actions?
你能幫你嬸嬸在相親網站上註冊賬號
Can you help your aunt create an online dating profile
讓她偶爾出去約個會嗎
so she can get out of the dang house once in a while?
當你聞到美食時 你能飄飄欲僊嗎
Can you float through the air when you smell a delicious pie?
-你夠堅強嗎 -夠無情嗎
- Can you be strong? - Ruthless?
-夠自律嗎  -我不知道 或許吧
- Disciplined? - I don't know. Maybe.
-心靈感應 -展現你的勇氣 士兵
- Psychic? - Show me some moxie, soldier!
最重要的是 不管你被打趴下幾次
Above all, no matter how many times you get hit,
你能站起來嗎
can you get back up?
當蜘蛛俠倒地時
'Cause when a Spider-Man is on the floor...
當你堅持不下去時
When you think you can't keep goin'...
-起來 邁爾斯  -起來 邁爾斯 你能做到的
- Come on, Miles. - Come on. You can do it.
-你能做到的  -夥計們 行了
- You can do this. - Guys, cool it.
-起來 邁爾斯 你能做到的  -快起來 邁爾斯
- Come on. You can do it! - Get up, Miles.
拜託 邁爾斯 站起來
Come on, Miles. Get up.
你不能自欺欺人
You need to be more honest with yourself about this.
他還沒準備好 這很明顯
He's not ready. It's obvious.
行不通 他只是個孩子
There's no way. He's just a kid.
如果他不行
If he can't do this,
我們就得留下替他完成任務
we have to stay and do it for him.
他在哪裏聽的到我們說他
He's looking right at us while we talk about him.
邁爾斯
Miles?
看到沒 他真
You see that? He can, um...
的會隱身
He can turn invisible.
♪ When it gets dark Outside ♪
♪ In you I confide ♪
♪ You help me face my demons I won't hide... ♪
邁爾斯 你怎麼回事
Miles, what is going on with you?
大家都沒有你的消息  我們不知道你是怎麼回事
Nobody's heard from you. We don't know what's going on.
如果你有事瞞著我們 趕緊坦白
If you're hidin' something from us, you need to come clean.
馬上打給我
You call me back. Now.
他也不接我的電話
He's not answering me either.
我是艾倫 我要出城幾天
It's Aaron. I'm outta town for a few days.
回來再打給你 再見
I'll hit you when I'm back. Peace.
艾倫 我是傑夫
Aaron, it's Jeff.
如果你有邁爾斯的消息 馬上打給我
Look, I need you to call me if you've heard from Miles.
他對你
He has a...
他對你總是那麼信任
He has a soft spot for you,
我們和他失去聯繫了
and we haven't heard from him.
如果不是緊急情況 我是不會找你的
And you know I wouldn't reach out if this wasn't important.
希望一切都好
Hope you're good.
親愛的艾倫叔叔
Dear Uncle Aaron.
我得去完成一件事 但我不知道能不能行
I gotta do something, and I don't know if I can do it.
我很害怕 叔叔
I'm scared, man.
我受夠了讓所有人失望
I'm just tired of lettin' everybody down.
你是我唯一能夠傾訴的人
You're the only one I can talk to.
真希望你能在這裏
I just wish you were here.
你好 菲斯克先生
Hello, Mr. Fisk.
我從隧道哪裏拿到了監控錄像
I've got the security tapes from the tunnel right here.
只要他還在這裏 我會找到他的
If the kid's out there, I'll find him.
你瞭解我的 先生 我從不放棄
You know me, sir. I don't ever quit.
♪ Personal insanity They gotta like the ally ♪
♪ Turn it up Against the rally ♪
♪ You're running in While they're counting ♪
♪ Even score, got the tally Knock 'em off at the finale ♪
♪ Go, go! They don't want it, yeah ♪
♪ They don't want it, yeah ♪
這個是
This is...
-紫色 -不是
- Purple. - No.
-藍色 -不是
- Blue? - No.
有邁爾斯的消息嗎
Has anyone heard from Miles?
他只是需要冷靜一下 我瞭解那孩子
Look, he's just clearing his head. I know the kid.
他能搞得定
He's got what it takes.
我敢打賭他一定會跨過那扇門
I bet you he's gonna come back through that door,
振作起來 準備還迎戰
recharged and ready to fight.
-我叔叔  -嘿 你去哪裏了
- My uncle. - Hey, where have you been?
我的叔叔艾倫 他是個徘徊者
My uncle Aaron, he's the Prowler.
-慢慢說  -他替金並做事
- Slow down, Miles. - He works for Kingpin.
他想要殺了我
He tried to kill me!
這劇情也太簡單粗暴了吧
This is a pretty hard-core origin story.
沒事的 沒事的 我們會弄明白的
It's okay. We're gonna figure it out.
-有人跟蹤你嗎 -不 我想應該沒有
- Were you followed? - No, I don't think so.
-地方不錯 真是溫馨 -好極了 是麗芙
- Cute place. Real homey. - Oh, great. It's Liv.
我想我被跟蹤了
I guess I was followed.
哦 不
Oh, no.
快走 邁爾斯
Get out of here, kid.
你闖大禍了 小子 太粗心了
You messed up bigtime, kid. Very sloppy.
看看這些可憐的小蜘蛛 讓我猜猜 你是蝎子  我們是蜘蛛 算是遠親
Let me guess. You're Scorpion. Well, we're the Spider gang.
你們介不介意到外面解決
Would you mind taking this outside?
我們跳起舞來從不挑場子
We don't pick the ballroom, we just dance.
那個就交給我吧
Ooh, I think I'll be taking that.
小傢伙 來吧 準備受死吧
Stand, niñito, dale. Preparate a morir.
天啊 愚蠢的墊子
Man, stupid pillows.
都說讓你們出去解決了
I said, take it outside!
我來
I got it!
交給我 夥計  別碰那個孩子
I got this, buddy. Leave the kid alone!
不 不
No, no, no! No!
快跑
You gotta go, man.
所有車輛請注意 發生騷亂事件
All vehicles in the area, we have a disturbance
嫌疑人為蜘蛛俠們
involving multiple Spiderpeople?
收到 這就去
Yeah. On my way.
把它交給我
Give me that thing.
別傻了 小子 快交給我
Don't be stupid, kid. Hand it over, now!
你無路可逃了
Nowhere left to run.
邁爾斯
Miles?
艾倫叔叔
Uncle Aaron.
不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
求你了 艾倫叔叔
Please, Uncle Aaron.
徘徊者
Prowler.
你還在等什麼 了結他
What are you waitin' for? Finish it.
快離開這裏
Get out of here!
不
No.
邁爾斯
Miles.
艾倫叔叔
Uncle Aaron.
這都是我的錯
This is my fault.
不 邁爾斯
No, Miles.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
是我騙了你 我想讓你崇拜我
I wanted you to look up to me.
是我讓你失望了
I let you down, man. I let you down.
你是我們中最棒的 邁爾斯
You're the best of all of us, Miles.
你有屬於自己的路
You're on your way.
你要堅持下去
Just keep going.
堅持下去
撐住
Hands up!
舉起手 把手舉起來
Put your arms up. Now!
轉過來
Turn around.
嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey!
艾倫 不 不
Aaron. Aaron, no. No!
各單位注意
All units.
全境搜捕一名新蜘蛛俠
I want an APB on a new Spider-Man.
嘿 夥計
Hey, bud.
你沒事吧
You okay?
我們都經歷過
We've all been there. You know,
我失去的是我本叔叔
for me it was my Uncle Ben.
我失去的是我的本傑明叔叔
For me, it was my Uncle Benjamin.
我失去的是我的爸爸
For me, it was my father.
我失去的是我最好的朋友
For me, it was my best friend.
邁爾斯 對我們而言最難接受的就是
Miles, the hardest thing about this job is
你不可能每次都救得了所有人
you can't always save everybody.
這都是我的錯 你們不會理解
Look, it was my fault. You wouldn't understand.
邁爾斯 我們或許是這世上唯一能夠理解你的人
Miles, we're probably the only ones who do understand.
糟糕
Oh, no.
♪ Who in here trying To start a riot? ♪
往那邊 往那邊
That way, that way.
另一邊 另一邊 另一邊
Other way, other way, other way, other way.
♪ Who that swinging In the air? ♪
嘿 夥計
Hey there.
你們這裏動物會說話嗎
Do animals talk in this dimension?
我可不想嚇著他
'Cause I don't wanna freak him out.
♪ Let's stand up, stand up You better just fix your... ♪
你們怎麼了
What's going on?
再見 邁爾斯
Bye, Miles.
邁爾斯 我是來道別的
Miles, I came to say goodbye.
可以在對撞機哪裏道別啊
We can say goodbye at the collider.
你沒明白 你得留在這裏
You're not getting it. You're staying here.
我必須去 這樣你們才能回去
I need to be there. So you can all go home.
他們是要回家了 邁爾斯 我會一個人留下
They are going home, Miles. I'm the only one stayin'.
你要代替我 留下來的話你會死的
You're taking my place? If you stay here, you'll die.
我必須完成我該做的事
I'm doing what needs to be done.
我希望自己能親口告訴你
I just wanted you to hear it from me.
那瑪麗 簡呢
What about MJ?
不是所有的事情都會有結果
Not everything works out, kid.
我需要小玩意
I need the goober.
請不要逼我從你那裏搶過來
Please don't make me take it from you.
這不公平
That's not fair!
你去告訴他們我能做到
You gotta tell them I can do this.
這不是他們的決定
It wasn't their decision.
我要讓金並付出代價  你必須讓我回去報仇
I gotta make Kingpin pay! You have to let me make him pay!
你這樣就等於去送死
Miles, you're gonna get yourself killed.
可我準備好了 我保證
But I'm ready. I promise!
那你現在就來電我
Then venom-strike me right now.
或者隱藏自己 說隱身就隱身 然後從我身邊走過
Or turn invisible on command so you can get past me.
聽著 我知道你很想報仇 孩子
Look, I know how much you want this, kid.
可憐的小傢伙
Poor little guy.
可你還沒準備好
But you don't have it yet.
對不起
I'm sorry.
彼得 怎麼才知道自己準備好了
When will I know I'm ready?
你不會知道 這是種信念
You won't. It's a leap of faith.
就這麼簡單 邁爾斯
That's all it is, Miles.
一種信念
A leap of faith.
邁爾斯
Miles.
邁爾斯 是爸爸
Miles, it's your dad.
把門打開好嗎
Please open the door.
邁爾斯 我看得到你的影子
Miles, I can see your shadow movin' around.
好吧 也對 我能理解 你還在生我的氣
Yeah, okay, I get it. I get it. You're still ignoring me.
我們能聊幾句嗎
Look, can we talk for a minute?
有件事
Something...
Something happened to...
有時候人與人之間會變得疏遠
Look, sometimes people drift apart, Miles.
我不希望這發生在我們身上 好嗎
And I don't want that to happen to us, okay?
我知道我一直沒能按照你希望的方式和你相處
I know I don't always do what you need me to do
可我看得到你身上的閃光點
or say what you need me to say.
這很了不起 所以我才會逼你
I see this spark in you. It's amazing. It's why I push you.
可這是你的人生
But it's yours.
不管你怎麼選擇 你都是最棒的
Whatever you choose to do with it, you'll be great.
回頭記得打給我 好嗎
Look, call me when you can. Okay?
我愛你
I love you.
這次你不用也說我愛你
You don't have to say it back, though.
♪ 200 miles per hour With a blindfold on ♪
♪ Mama always asking "Where did I go wrong?" ♪
這麼晚才到
Took you long enough.
♪ Ah, what's up, danger? ♪
我看得到你身上的閃光點
I see this spark in you.
這很了不起
It's amazing.
不管你怎麼選擇 你都事最棒的
Whatever you choose to do with it, you'll be great.
我們家的人從那個不逃避問題
Our family doesn't run from things.
你是我們中最棒的 邁爾斯 你有屬於自己的路
You're the best of all of us, Miles. You're on your way.
堅持下去
Just keep going.
怎麼才知道自己準備好了
When do I know I'm Spider-Man?
你不會知道
You won't.
就這麼簡單 邁爾斯
That's all it is, Miles.
一種信念
A leap of faith.
♪ Like, what's up, danger? ♪
我自己做的
Made 'em myself.
帶起來非常合身
They fit perfectly.
- ♪ Can't stop me now ♪ - ♪ Traveled 200 miles ♪
♪ I'm knockin' at your door And I don't really care ♪
- ♪ If you ain't done wrong ♪ - ♪ I said I got you now ♪
♪ Come on, what's up, danger? ♪
♪ Don't be a stranger ♪
♪ I'm right here at your door ♪
♪ I won't leave, I want more ♪
♪ What's up, danger? ♪
♪ Yeah, what's up, danger? ♪
♪ Can't stop me now ♪
♪ 'Cause I like high G's Sister, I might lose ♪
♪ I like it all on the edge Just like you, hey ♪
♪ I like tall buildings So I can leap off of 'em ♪
♪ I go hard with it No matter how dark it is ♪
♪ Come on, what's up, danger? ♪
金並有一部私人電梯
Kingpin has a private elevator entrance
可以從頂樓直接通往對撞機哪裏
from his penthouse to the collider below.
沒想到還會有觀眾
Didn't count on having an audience.
開什麼玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
謝謝  很榮幸今晚能和
Thank you. It's nice to be with you this evening
大家一起紀念蜘蛛俠
to celebrate Spider-Man.
我們曾經是很好的朋友 他就像
He and I were very close.
-真是個豬頭 -我聽得到你說話
- What a pig. - I'm right here.
等等 看看那些服務生的打扮
Hold on. Get a load of how the waiters are dressed.
真沒品味 不過
It's in poor taste, but...
不會這麼容易吧
It can't be that easy.
就是這麼容易
It's that easy.
很感謝今晚瑪麗 簡 帕克
I just wanna thank Mary Jane Parker
可以出席我們的晚宴
for being here this evening.
瑪麗 簡
Mj?
集中精神  那不是你的瑪麗 簡 彼得 懂嗎
Pay attention. It's not your MJ, Peter, okay?
抱歉 我馬上回來
I'm sorry, I'll be right back.
彼得 別過去 相信我
Peter! Come here. Trust me.
我也經歷過  你要向前看
I've been there. You gotta move on, buddy.
就一下下 我只想和她
It will take one second. Let me just... Oh!
你好
- Hello. - Oh, wow.
能不能
Um... I just wondered
麻煩給12號桌加點麵包
if we could have some more bread at table 12.
好的
Yeah.
我想說 我真的很抱歉
I'm just... I'm really sorry.
不用抱歉 只是麵包而已
Oh! Don't be sorry. It's just bread.
你需要我的時候 我沒能出現
I wasn't there for you when you needed me.
我甚至都沒盡力
- Mm-hmm. - I didn't even try.
沒關係 我想我該走了
That's fine. You know, I should really get going.
我知道我能做的更好
I know I could do better
如果我還有機會
if I just had another chance
我一定會給你 你值得擁有的那些麵包
to give you the bread that you deserve.
你沒事吧
Are you okay?
女士 麵包一會就會送到
We'll take care of that bread right now.
很高興能夠和你聊天
Well, it's been nice talking to you.
為了你 他們應該在這裏鋪滿新鮮的麵包
For you, they should fill this place up with fresh bread.
-你還好吧 夥計 -是的 我很好
- You all right, man? - Oh, yeah. Totally.
那就好 我們可沒空管麵包的事
Good, 'cause we are not getting any bread.
我只是為家人無法看到
I'm just sorry my family can't see
今晚的情況感到遺憾
what we're doing here tonight.
初始化初級點火序列
Initializing primary ignition sequence.
睡吧
Sleep.
啟動程序
Start the sequence.
上傳瓦娜沙 菲斯克和 理查德 菲斯克的基因序列
Uploading Vanessa Fisk and Richard Fisk DNA sequence.
開始搜索空間匹配
Beginning scan for dimensional matches.
二級點火倒計時開始 五 四
Secondary ignition in five, four,
三 二 一
three, two, one.
彼得 你不必留下來 我能搞定
Peter, you don't have to stay behind. I can do it.
沒關係
It's okay.
我已經決定了
I've made up my mind.
我會把小玩意插進去 控制光波
I'll put the goober in and take over the beam.
等你們都走了 我就炸了它
After you're gone, I'll blow it up.
祝你們好運
Good luck, guys.
他們知道我們在這裏
They know we're here.
很高興又見面了 彼得
Nice to see you again, Peter.
我來掩護你
I got you covered!
這些傢伙真礙事
These guys are the pits.
為什麼總是這麼難
Why is this always difficult?
你要去哪裏 彼得
Where you going, Peter?
有什麼遺言嗎
Any last words?
能給我一分鐘思考一下嗎 帶筆了嗎
Can I get a minute to think about it? You have a pen?
再見了 彼得 帕克
Goodbye, Peter Parker.
誰在哪裏
Who did that?!
-邁爾斯 -蜘蛛俠
- Miles? - Spider-Man?
邁爾斯 你學會控制自己了
Wow, Miles. You're doing it on command!
也是時候了 對吧
It's about time, right?
-看看誰來了 -你做到了
- Look who's here! - You figured it out.
我愛你 真為你感到驕傲
I love you! I am so proud of you!
我想要孩子了
Do I want kids
好吧 我忘記他們了
Oh, yeah, I forgot about her.
情況看起來可不妙
Well, that doesn't look promising.
對 確實不妙
No, it doesn't.
找到基因匹配了 等等
I've got genetic matches. Hold on.
風險太高了
It's too risky.
閉上嘴 快打開
Shut up and turn it up.
-在你左邊 -在你右邊
- On your left! - On your right!
五點鐘方向 三點鐘 兩點鐘
I got five o'clock! Three o'clock! Two o'clock!
所有方向
Every direction!
快去避難所 我馬上過去
Get to a shelter. I'll be right there.
我打給學校 可怎麼都打不通
I tried the school, but I can't get through.
夥計們 你們看到了嗎
Guys, are you seeing this?
看起來像是我們的宇宙正在涌向我們
Looks like our dimensions are coming to us.
看起來還挺酷 不是嗎
Does look cool though, right?
我們得回去到上面去
We gotta get back up there.
你就這麼點本事嗎
Is that all you got?
看來你只會嘴上說說
You gonna fight or you just bumping gums?
你這個欠扁的臭烏龜
You hard-boiled turtle slapper!
什麼玩意 愚蠢的卡通人物嗎
What are you, some kind of silly cartoon?
你對卡通人物有意見嗎
You got a problem with cartoons?
看錘
Blammo!
Aww...
現在覺得卡通人物怎麼樣
Did that feel like a cartoon?
格溫
Gwen!
戰服不錯
I like your suit.
謝謝 我自己做的
Thanks. I made it myself.
真可愛 夥計們 現在抓緊了
That was adorable, team! Now, hold on tight!
準備好 夥計們 這將會是場苦戰
Buckle up, guys. This is gonna take a while.
好吧 當我沒說
All right. Never mind.
去做個了結吧
Let's end this thing.
夥計們 交給我吧
Guys, I got it.
讓我去 小玩意還在我的
I'll go. I'm the one with the goo...
居然上那小子的套了
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
別關顧著聽 要仔細看
Don't watch the mouth. Watch the hands.
-邁爾斯 -小心
- Miles! - Be careful!
還挺刺激的
That was crazy.
這都是我們教他的 對吧
We taught him that, right?
我可沒教過他 更不可能是你教的
I didn't teach him that. And you definitely didn't.
沒事吧
You okay?
走吧
Come on.
嘿 夥計們 我控制住光波了
Guys, I got control of the beam! Get up here!
警報 量子極性正在逆轉
Alert! Quantum polarity has been reversed.
看來是時候了
Guess this is it.
好吧 能找到同伴真好
Well, nice to know we're not alone.
-對吧 -沒錯
- Right? - Yeah.
我打開了入口 你先走 潘妮
I got the portal open. You first, Peni.
謝謝你 邁爾斯
Thank you, Miles.
我們倆都是
From both of us.
我想說 我愛你們大家
I, uh, love you all.
我會把這小方塊帶回去
I'm taking this cube thing with me.
雖然還不太會玩
I don't understand it.
但我會搞懂的
But I will.
這個送給你
I want you to have this.
可以放在口袋裏
It'll fit in your pocket.
朋友們 就到這裏吧
That's all, folks.
他可以這麼說嗎 不侵權嗎
Is he allowed to say that, legally?
現在能說我喜歡你的髮型了嗎
Do I get to like the hairdo now?
你知道我比你大吧
You know I'm older than you.
雖然只有15個月 但我還是挺介意這點的
15 months, but it's pretty significant if you ask me.
好吧 愛因斯坦說過 時間是相對的 不是嗎
Well, Einstein said time was relative, right?
聰明
Nice.
朋友
Friends?
Friends.
真棒
Cool.
回頭見 蜘蛛俠
See you around, Spider-Man.
該你了
Your turn.
對 對 沒錯
Yeah, yeah. Right.
你那裏都別想去
You're not going anywhere!
我去拖住他 你把機器關掉
I'll hold him off. You shut this down.
彼得 計劃不是這樣的
Peter, that wasn't the deal!
按綠色按鈕 千萬不要等我
Push the green button! Do not wait for me!
-你在做什麼 -彼得 你必須回家
- What are you doing? - You gotta go home!
這傢伙會殺了你的 我不能看著蜘蛛俠死
This guy could kill you! I can't let Spider-Man die.
我也不能
Neither can I.
不會有事的
It's okay.
對 我不會讓你有事的
Yeah, it is okay.
你得回去 夥計
You gotta go home, man.
我怎麼知道這次會不會再被我搞砸
How do I know I'm not gonna mess it up again?
你不會知道
You won't.
對
Right.
這是種信念
It's a leap of faith.
真不賴 小子
Not bad, kid.
金並
Kingpin!
不行
Nope!
抱歉 那是作弊
Sorry! That's cheating.
再見
Adios.
我的去那個地方
I gotta get to that button.
糟糕了
Oh, no.
孤軍奮戰沒想像中那麼容易 對吧
Not so easy doing it on your own, is it?
我迫不及待想再殺一個蜘蛛俠
I can't wait to kill one more Spider-Man.
-我在哪裏 -什麼
- Where am I? - What?
威爾遜
Wilson?
-這就是你想要的嗎 -你在做什麼
- Is this what you want, man? - What are you doing?
瓦娜沙
Vanessa. Vanessa.
-我們怎麼會在這裏  -我不知道 理查德
- What are we doing here? - I don't know, Richard.
是我 你知道我的
It's me. You know me.
快離開這裏
We're leaving now.
別走
Don't go.
留下來
Stay with me.
求你了
Please!
我不會讓你阻止我的 這次絕對不行
You're not stopping this. Not today.
我就是要阻止你 就現在
I am stopping this. Right now!
我需要支援
I need backup.
加油
Come on.
真正的蜘蛛俠都戰勝不了我
The real Spider-Man couldn't even beat me.
你算什麼
You're nothing!
你奪走了我的家人
You took my family.
現在 我要讓你也見不到你的家人
And now I'm gonna make sure you never see yours again.
站起來 蜘蛛俠
Get up, Spider-Man.
Get up! Come on!
拜託 拜託 拜託
Come on. Come on. Come on.
我不會離開我的家人
I'll always have my family.
聽過搭肩膀這招嗎
You ever hear of the shoulder touch?
什麼
What?
嘿
Hey.
嘿 金並 幫我按綠色按鈕
Hey, Kingpin! Push the green button for me!
邁爾斯 邁爾斯 你沒事吧
Miles? Miles? Are you okay?
放心 我沒事
Yeah, I'm okay.
你現在應該很忙 所以
You're probably busy...
不 我有空 我有空
No! I can talk, I can talk.
我之前去找你是因為
Look, so I came by earlier because...
-你叔叔 他 -我知道 爸爸
- Your uncle... - I know, Dad.
我很難過
I am so sorry.
我知道
Yeah.
知道是誰幹的嗎
Do you know who did it?
我以為我知道
I thought I did.
可我錯了
But I was wrong.
聽著 邁爾斯 我在門口說的那些
Look, Miles, what I said at the door,
不只是說說而已
it wasn't just talk.
聽著 知道嗎 我在想我們可以
Look, you know, I was thinking
找一堵不錯的牆
maybe we could find a nice wall,
私人所有的 比如警察局那堵
privately owned, like at the police station,
這樣你就可以把你的作品 "丟到"牆上去了
and you could "Throw up" Some of your art.
我實在不擅長說這些
Man, I'm bad at this.
好吧 邁爾斯 邁爾斯 還在嗎
Okay, Miles. Miles? You there?
真是的 什麼破信號
Oh, come on, man. C-Mobile!
-警官 -蜘蛛俠
- Officer. - Spider-Man!
我想說 剛才真是
Listen, down there, that was...
我是說我欠你一個
I mean, I owe you...
好吧
Okay!
很期待和你並肩作戰
I look forward to workin' with you.
對 我想我也是
Yeah, me, too. I guess.
雖然我不贊成你的方式
I don't approve of your methods,
不過想法不同也許也能擦出火花
but we're just gonna have to agree to disagree.
感謝你今晚的英勇行為
Thank you for your bravery tonight.
我愛你
I love you.
等等 什麼
Wait, what?
看看你身後
And look behind you!
沒錯 是很酷 對
All right. Cool. Yeah.
謝謝你 蜘蛛俠
Thanks, Spider-Man.
蜘蛛俠 謝謝 謝謝
Spider-Man, a su servicio. Thank you.
嘿 夥計 你好嗎
Hey, man. What's up, little man?
是新蜘蛛俠
New Spider-Man.
對 沒錯 我是新蜘蛛俠
Yeah. Yeah, I'm the new Spider-Man.
看好了
Check it out.
Whoa!
剛才那是設計好的
That was part of the move.
好了 我們最後再來一次
Okay, let's do this one last time, yeah?
這次是真的最後一次
For real this time. This is it.
我叫邁爾斯 莫拉萊斯
My name is Miles Morales.
我被一隻受過輻射的蜘蛛咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
於是就在最近
And for like two days,
我成為了這裏唯一的蜘蛛俠
I've been the one and only Spider-Man.
剩下的你們都知道了
I think you know the rest.
我寫完了論文
I finished my essay.
救了不少人
Saved a bunch of people.
撞到過無人機
Got hit by a drone.
我和我爸完成了這個
I did this with my dad.
最後來見見我的室友
Met my roommate. Finally.
在我爸爸永遠找不到的地方貼貼紙
Slapped a sticker where my dad's never gonna find it.
當我感到孤單
And when I feel alone,
感覺沒人能理解自己時
like no one understands what I'm going through,
我知道我的朋友們會懂我
I remember my friends who get it.
我從沒想過自己能夠做到這些
I never thought I'd be able to do any of this stuff.
可我做到了
But I can.
任何人都能戴上這個面具
Anyone can wear the mask.
你也可以做到
You could wear the mask.
如果以前你沒想過 希望現在可以
If you didn't know that before, I hope you do now.
因為我是蜘蛛俠
'Cause I'm Spider-Man.
但我不是唯一的
And I'm not the only one.
絕對不是
Not by a long shot.
♪ Needless to say I keep her in check ♪
♪ She was all bad-bad Nevertheless ♪
♪ Callin' it quits now Baby, I'm a wreck... ♪
邁爾斯
Miles. Miles!
你有空嗎
You got a minute?
♪ Stepped out of my zone ♪
♪ I had to get out all alone ♪
♪ And figure it out on my own ♪
♪ And I know what I really want now ♪
♪ Can't stop me Can't break me ♪
♪ What don't kill me Gon' make me ♪
♪ Shoot for the stars No safety ♪
♪ And now I see clear in HD ♪
- ♪ Gotta go hard ♪ - ♪ Gotta go hard ♪
- ♪ I ain't got time to waste ♪ - ♪ I ain't got time ♪
- ♪ I gotta go high ♪ - ♪ Gotta go high ♪
- ♪ I gotta elevate ♪ - ♪ I gotta elevate ♪
- ♪ They wanna fight ♪ - ♪ They wanna fight ♪
- ♪ I'm just gon' let 'em hate ♪ - ♪ I'm just gon' let 'em hate ♪
- ♪ I gotta go high ♪ - ♪ Gotta go high ♪
- ♪ I gotta elevate ♪ - ♪ I gotta elevate ♪
♪ You gotta choose a side You gotta choose a side ♪
♪ You better keep You better do what's right ♪
♪ Or you gonna lose the fight ♪
- ♪ You gonna ♪ - ♪ Gotta go hard ♪
♪ Gotta choose a side ♪
♪ I'm gonna elevate ♪
- ♪ You better ♪ - ♪ Gotta go high ♪
- ♪ You better do what's right ♪ - ♪ I gotta elevate ♪
♪ Heroes never die ♪
♪ I'm a web slinger To a gunslinger ♪
♪ No millimeter This is my arena ♪
♪ I'm the black widow With the best stinger ♪
♪ And I'll make you scream Like a bad singer ♪
♪ I'm everything that you Wanna be plus more ♪
♪ Since there's No heroes anymore ♪
♪ Jump out the window Him with the mask on ♪
♪ Who the bad man That our man gotta bash on? ♪
♪ Oh, we'll never link up Blink and you will see us ♪
♪ Young prince 'bout to ink up See me in the NYC ♪
♪ You can never swing by me ♪
♪ Oh, we'll never link up Blink and you will see us ♪
♪ Young prince 'bout to ink up See me in the NYC ♪
♪ Home of the B.I.G., yo ♪
♪ They just slander me I just plan to be ♪
♪ Something powerful For my family ♪
♪ Tried to balance life And my sanity ♪
♪ Show a different side Of humanity ♪
♪ So amazing, keep upraising ♪
♪ Save you from A home invasion ♪
♪ Chasing robbers From the bank ♪
♪ You facing friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man ♪
♪ Gotta go hard ♪
- ♪ I ain't got time to waste ♪ - ♪ I ain't got time ♪
- ♪ I gotta go high ♪ - ♪ Gotta go high ♪
- ♪ I gotta elevate ♪ - ♪ I gotta elevate ♪
- ♪ They wanna fight ♪ - ♪ They wanna fight ♪
- ♪ I'm just gon' let 'em hate ♪ - ♪ I'm just gon' let 'em hate ♪
- ♪ I gotta go high ♪ - ♪ Gotta go high ♪
- ♪ I gotta elevate ♪ - ♪ I gotta elevate ♪
♪ Okay, I fight crime Through the nighttime ♪
♪ When the lights shine I go python ♪
♪ I'm falling on My last lifeline ♪
♪ There's no way In my right mind ♪
♪ My city up on my back tight ♪
♪ How can I possibly Act right? ♪
♪ I'm Robin Hood I'm the black knight ♪
♪ I know you heard 'Bout my last fight ♪
♪ 'Cause I win Over and over again ♪
♪ Battling evil I'm hoping to win ♪
♪ Fighting my demons I'm nice for a reason ♪
♪ Enticed with the bleeding I'm showing my sins ♪
♪ How can you expect me To stay sane? ♪
♪ Protect me My technique go X speed ♪
♪ On highways and Jet Skis ♪
♪ Look, I ain't got no time To be hanging around nobody ♪
♪ Trying to figure out If they good or evil ♪
♪ I'm fighting the crime Saving your lives ♪
♪ One at a time I'm killing the rhymes ♪
♪ I do it for the people ♪
♪ I'm Peter Parker Running through The Six ♪
♪ With a bag full of tricks You better choose a side ♪
♪ I can promise you I will not lose this time ♪
♪ I did it all independent Now we winning ♪
♪ I got my homeys Cooking in the kitchen ♪
♪ We gon' have to win And give us the business ♪
♪ The world is mine and you Gon' have to pay me attention ♪
♪ I did everything That I did on my own ♪
♪ I'm the only one for real There can never be a clone ♪
♪ Better talk to me nice Better watch your tone ♪
♪ And I'm putting on For my home slice ♪
♪ So I gotta go hard ♪
♪ I gotta elevate ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ I went from boy to a man, Why? ♪
♪ Officer sure had to Stand down ♪
♪ But I had to make A perfect plan ♪
- ♪ I'm on a wave ♪ - ♪ Brave, brave ♪
♪ I had to fight For the city ♪
♪ For the city ♪
- ♪ I had to fight for people ♪ - ♪ For the people ♪
♪ You gotta do What all leaders do, go ♪
♪ Everyone here We been needing you ♪
♪ I know you can be a hero 'Cause I seen you do it ♪
♪ This is the time We needed you ♪
♪ Everyone is here To see you move ♪
♪ We want it, we want it We want it, we want it ♪
- ♪ We put our wallet away ♪ - ♪ Wallet ♪
♪ And every time Each one of you ♪
♪ Through the city You were saving the day, go ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ We gotta fight For the town, town ♪
♪ Now there's no feelings allowed, allowed ♪
♪ Everyone cheer in the crowd ♪
♪ Bought 'em so well I'm over the clouds ♪
- ♪ We gotta fight for the city ♪ - ♪ City ♪
- ♪ Competition was lethal ♪ - ♪ Lethal ♪
- ♪ Honestly, it's no biggie ♪ - ♪ Biggie ♪
♪ I had to do What all leaders do ♪
♪ Uh-oh They don't want it, man ♪
♪ Uh-oh They don't wanna know ♪
♪ Promise, uh-oh They don't want it, man ♪
♪ Uh-oh, they can't Handle my powers ♪
♪ They always hate on us ♪
♪ But they can't do it Without us ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We gotta clean up These city streets ♪
- ♪ We don't accept defeat ♪ - ♪ 'Feat ♪
♪ We keep on going Until we win ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ All of 'em weak In the knees ♪
♪ Scary how lights When they freeze ♪
♪ Well, we keep on going Until we win ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ Well ♪
Ha!
♪ This morning I woke up ♪
♪ In a fortress of distortion ♪
♪ I'm at war with my emotions ♪
♪ I'm at war with They enforce me ♪
♪ Trying to fight for what's Right, and got sidetracked ♪
♪ Where your mind at? Never mind that ♪
♪ Got me thinking a blink You swim and you sinking ♪
♪ You wouldn't, you leave me Here for my loaded weapon ♪
♪ I still owe my brother My present protection ♪
♪ My prayer, my sights So I'm doing what's right ♪
♪ And I ask you no questions ♪
♪ I wanna be home-free ♪
♪ Where's one that was lonely ♪
♪ But I'm ready and waiting ♪
♪ For my day of salvation And I'm patient ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ I'm coming home, now ♪
♪ I'm coming home ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ My rebel lone yell ♪
♪ My rebel lone ♪
♪ They looking for saviors I'm looking for safety ♪
♪ They never gonna break me Take me ♪
♪ Down on my knees, believe ♪
♪ I'm never gonna beg Or plead ♪
♪ I never say never But I guarantee ♪
♪ Gather my strength Goin' hard in the paint ♪
♪ Paint some more pictures Put on display ♪
♪ I'm a get they don't Get them my check ♪
♪ Can't take me down now ♪
♪ My feet on the ground now ♪
♪ Punchin' 'em on down now ♪
♪ Say it out loud now ♪
♪ Say it out loud Are you ready for war? ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ I'm coming home now ♪
♪ I'm coming home ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ My rebel lone yell ♪
♪ My rebel lone ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh, Spidey-bells Spidey-bells ♪
♪ Swinging through Midtown ♪
♪ Oh, what fun to sling a web ♪
♪ And take the bad guys down ♪
♪ Spidey-bells, Spidey-bells ♪
♪ Quipping all the time ♪
♪ Oh, what fun To swing around ♪
♪ New York While fighting crime ♪
♪ Swinging through The streets ♪
♪ On a web of spider silk ♪
♪ Kicking all the butts ♪
♪ Of villains and their ilk ♪
♪ Bombs from Goblins fling Fling ♪
♪ Pumpkins blooming bright Bright ♪
♪ How hard it is To consistently bring ♪
♪ Peace to New York all night ♪
♪ Oh, Spidey-bells Might be swell ♪
♪ To do more than fight crime ♪
♪ I got a lot of qualities That don't get much airtime ♪
♪ I can sing, I can dance I tell jokes, I act ♪
♪ I get big, big, big deal ♪
♪ If my agent called me back ♪
♪ Why did I agree ♪
♪ To do this stupid song? ♪
♪ I have a degree ♪
♪ In chemical engineering ♪
You're a bit late.
We can't all be everywhere at once.
Little text might've been nice.
I was gone for less than two hours. What happened?
Okay. I know what it looks like.
- But here's the good news. - Oh, here we go.
The multiverse didn't collapse.
- Oh, cool! - Little touch and go.
But it worked out.
Great story. Did you finish the goober?
It's not a goober. It's a gizmo.
Do you always have to call me out?
It's just really frustrating and bums me out.
Don't get excited, Miguel.
- It's just a prototype. - Not excited.
But you could be the first person
to make an autonomous multiverse jump.
Or the last.
So we're just gonna roll the dice on this?
So, what you do you say, pal? Where you want to go first?
Let's start at the beginning one last time.
Earth '67.
- Whoa! - What the...?
I'm Spider-Man.
- I need you to come with me. - Who the heck are you?
I just told you... Listen. I'm from the future.
- How dare you point at me! - You were pointing first.
- It's rude to point. - You're being very rude.
Which one pointed first?
Spider-Man pointed first. Obviously.
- You're pointing at me right now. - I'm not pointing.
Look at your finger.
I'm pointing out your pointing, which is different.
You haven't seen pointing.
You're accusing me of pointing while you're...!
-= www.OpenSubtitles.org =-